<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5"><character><version>37</version><uid>8814</uid><name>Wiz Lvl1</name><abilities>10,10,14,15,12,10,</abilities><hpMax>8</hpMax><hpCurrent>8</hpCurrent><unarmed>1</unarmed><race><name>Changeling</name><feat><name>Ability Score Increase</name><text>Either your Dexterity or your Intelligence increases by 1 (your choice).

 
Source: Wayfinder&#39;s Guide to Eberron, Chapter 3</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Change Appearance</name><text>As an action, you can transform your appearance or revert to your natural form. You can’t duplicate the appearance of a creature you’ve never seen, and you revert to your natural form if you die.
	You decide what you look like, including your height, weight, facial features, the sound of your voice, coloration, hair length, sex, and any other distinguishing characteristics. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You also can’t appear as a creature of a different size than you, and your basic shape stays the same; if you’re bipedal, you can’t use this trait to become quadrupedal, for instance. Your clothing and other equipment don’t change in appearance, size, or shape to match your new form, requiring you to keep a few extra outfits on hand to make the most compelling disguise possible.
	Even to the most astute observers, your ruse is usually indiscernible. If you rouse suspicion, or if a wary creature suspects something is amiss, you have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make to avoid detection.
 
Source: Wayfinder&#39;s Guide to Eberron, Chapter 3</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Changeling Instincts</name><text>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Intimidation, Insight, and Persuasion.
 
Source: Wayfinder&#39;s Guide to Eberron, Chapter 3</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Unsettling Visage</name><text>When a creature you can see makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the roll. You must use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses.
	Using this trait reveals your shapeshifting nature to any creature within 30 feet that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
 
Source: Wayfinder&#39;s Guide to Eberron, Chapter 3</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Divergent Persona</name><text>You gain proficiency with one tool of your choice. Define a unique identity associated with that proficiency; establish the name, race, gender, age, and other details. While you are in the form of this persona, the related proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses that proficiency.

 
Source: Wayfinder&#39;s Guide to Eberron, Chapter 3</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Languages</name><text>You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice.
 
Source: Wayfinder&#39;s Guide to Eberron, Chapter 3</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><mod><category>1</category><type>3</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><category>1</category><type>5</type><value>2</value></mod><spellAbility>6</spellAbility></race><background><name>Cloistered Scholar</name><proficiency>105</proficiency><feat><name>Description</name><text>As a child, you were inquisitive when your playmates were possessive or raucous. In your formative years, you found your way to one of Faerûn&#39;s great institutes of learning, where you were apprenticed and taught that knowledge is a more valuable treasure than gold or gems. Now you are ready to leave your home — not to abandon it, but to quest for new lore to add to its storehouse of knowledge. 
	The most well known of Faerûn&#39;s fonts of knowledge is Candlekeep. The great library is always in need of workers and attendants, some of whom rise through the ranks to assume roles of greater responsibility and prominence. You might be one of Candlekeep&#39;s own, dedicated to the curatorship of what is likely the most complete body of lore and history in all the world. Perhaps instead you were taken in by the scholars of the Vault of the Sages or the Map House in Silverymoon, and now you have struck out to increase your knowledge and to make yourself available to help those in other places who seek your expertise. You might be one of the few who aid Herald&#39;s Holdfast, helping to catalogue and maintain records of the information that arrives daily from across Faerûn.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Suggested Characteristics</name><text>Use the tables for the sage background in the Player&#39;s Handbook as the basis for your traits and motivations, modifying the entries when appropriate to suit your identity as a cloistered scholar. 
 
Your bond is almost certainly associated either with the place where you grew up or with the knowledge you hope to acquire through adventuring. Your ideal is no doubt related to how you view the quest for knowledge and truth — perhaps as a worthy goal in itself, or maybe as a means to a desirable end.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Starting Proficiencies</name><text>Your background grants you the following proficiencies.
 
Skills: History, plus your choice of one from among Arcana, Nature, and Religion
 
Languages: any two of your choice
 
Tools: none</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Library Access</name><text>Though others must often endure extensive interviews and significant fees to gain access to even the most common archives in your library, you have free and easy access to the majority of the library,, though it might also have repositories of lore that are too valuable, magical, or secret to permit anyone immediate access.
	You have a working knowledge of your cloister&#39;s personnel and bureaucracy, and you know how to navigate those connections with some ease.
	Additionally, you are likely to gain preferential treatment at other libraries across the Realms, as professional courtesy to a fellow scholar.
 
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 146</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Equipment</name><text>The scholar&#39;s robes of your cloister, a writing kit (small pouch with a quill, ink, folded parchment, and a small penknife), a borrowed book on the subject of your current study, and a pouch containing 10 gp.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Personality Trait</name><text>Choose or randomly determine

 
1. I use polysyllabic words that convey the impression of great erudition. 
 
2. I&#39;ve read every book in the world&#39;s greatest libraries-or I like to boast that I have. 
 
3. I&#39;m used to helping out those who aren&#39;t as smart as I am, and I patiently explain anything and everything to others. 
 
4. There&#39;s nothing I like more than a good mystery. 
 
5. I&#39;m willing to listen to every side of an argument before I make my own judgment. 
 
6. I... speak... slowly... when talking... to idiots,... which... almost... everyone... is... compared... to me. 
 
7. I am horribly, horribly awkward in social situations. 
 
8. I&#39;m convinced that people are always trying to steal my secrets. </text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Ideal</name><text>Choose or randomly determine

 
1. Knowledge: The path to power and self-improvement is through knowledge. (Neutral). 
 
2. Beauty: What is beautiful points us beyond itself toward what is true. (Good). 
 
3. Logic: Emotions must not cloud our logical thinking. (Lawful). 
 
4. No Limits: Nothing should fetter the infinite possibility inherent in all existence. (Chaotic). 
 
5. Power: Knowledge is the path to power and domination. (Evil). 
 
6. Self-Improvement: The goal of a life of study is the betterment of oneself. (Any). </text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Bond</name><text>Choose or randomly determine

 
1. It is my duty to protect my students. 
 
2. I have an ancient text that holds terrible secrets that must not fall into the wrong hands. 
 
3. I work to preserve a library, university, scriptorium, or monastery. 
 
4. My life&#39;s work is a series of tomes related to a specific field of lore. 
 
5. I&#39;ve been searching my whole life for the answer to a certain question. 
 
6. I sold my soul for knowledge. I hope to do great deeds and win it back.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Flaw</name><text>Choose or randomly determine

 
1. I am easily distracted by the promise of information. 
 
2. Most people scream and run when they see a demon. I stop and take notes on its anatomy. 
 
3. Unlocking an ancient mystery is worth the price of a civilization. 
 
4. I overlook obvious solutions in favor of complicated ones. 
 
5. I speak without really thinking through my words, invariably insulting others. 
 
6. I can&#39;t keep a secret to save my life, or anyone else&#39;s.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat></background><class><name>Wizard</name><wealth>4d4x10</wealth><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><proficiency>3</proficiency><proficiency>4</proficiency><proficiency>102</proficiency><proficiency>105</proficiency><numClassSkills>2</numClassSkills><armor>none</armor><weapons>daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</weapons><tools>none</tools><feat><name>Starting Wizard</name><text>As a 1st-level Wizard, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: none
• Weapons: daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
• Tools: none
• Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, and Religion
 
You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger
• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus
• (a) a scholar&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack
• A spellbook
 
Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 112</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. 
	 
Cantrips:
	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 4th level, and another at 10th level.
	 
Spellbook:
	At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
	 
Preparing and Casting Spells:
	The Wizard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you’re a 3rd-level wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination, chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell magic missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability:
	Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier 
	 
Ritual Casting:
	You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don’t need to have the spell prepared. 
	 
Spellcasting Focus:
	You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. 
	 
Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher:
	Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 114</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Spellbook</name><text>The spells of 1st level and higher that you add to your spellbook as you gain levels reflect the arcane research you conduct on your own, as well as intellectual breakthroughs you have had about the nature of the multiverse. You might find other spells during your adventures. You could discover a spell recorded on a scroll in an evil wizard’s chest, for example, or in a dusty tome in an ancient library.
	 
Copying a Spell into the Book:
	When you find a wizard spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your spellbook if it is of a spell level you can prepare and if you can spare the time to decipher and copy it.
	Copying that spell into your spellbook involves reproducing the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique system of notation used by the wizard who wrote it. You must practice the spell until you understand the sounds or gestures required, then transcribe it into your spellbook using your own notation.
	For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp. The cost represents material components you expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your other spells.
	 
Replacing the Book:
	You can copy a spell from your own spellbook into another book — for example, if you want to make a backup copy of your spellbook. This is just like copying a new spell into your spellbook, but faster and easier, since you understand your own notation and already know how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 10 gp for each level of the copied spell.
	If you lose your spellbook, you can use the same procedure to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new spellbook. Filling out the remainder of your spellbook requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this reason, many wizards keep backup spellbooks in a safe place.
	 
The Book’s Appearance:
	Your spellbook is a unique compilation of spells, with its own decorative flourishes and margin notes. It might be a plain, functional leather volume that you received as a gift from your master, a finely bound gilt-edged tome you found in an ancient library, or even a loose collection of notes scrounged together after you lost your previous spellbook in a mishap.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 114</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Arcane Recovery</name><text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.
	For example, if you’re a 4th-level wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><autolevel><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Starting Wizard</name><text>As a 1st-level Wizard, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: none
• Weapons: daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
• Tools: none
• Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, and Religion
 
You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger
• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus
• (a) a scholar&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack
• A spellbook
 
Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 112</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Multiclass Wizard</name><text>To multiclass as a Wizard, you must meet the following prerequisites:
• Intelligence 13
 
You gain the following proficiencies:
• none
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 163</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. 
	 
Cantrips:
	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 4th level, and another at 10th level.
	 
Spellbook:
	At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
	 
Preparing and Casting Spells:
	The Wizard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you’re a 3rd-level wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination, chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell magic missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability:
	Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier 
	 
Ritual Casting:
	You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don’t need to have the spell prepared. 
	 
Spellcasting Focus:
	You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. 
	 
Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher:
	Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 114</text></feat><feat><name>Spellbook</name><text>The spells of 1st level and higher that you add to your spellbook as you gain levels reflect the arcane research you conduct on your own, as well as intellectual breakthroughs you have had about the nature of the multiverse. You might find other spells during your adventures. You could discover a spell recorded on a scroll in an evil wizard’s chest, for example, or in a dusty tome in an ancient library.
	 
Copying a Spell into the Book:
	When you find a wizard spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your spellbook if it is of a spell level you can prepare and if you can spare the time to decipher and copy it.
	Copying that spell into your spellbook involves reproducing the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique system of notation used by the wizard who wrote it. You must practice the spell until you understand the sounds or gestures required, then transcribe it into your spellbook using your own notation.
	For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp. The cost represents material components you expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your other spells.
	 
Replacing the Book:
	You can copy a spell from your own spellbook into another book — for example, if you want to make a backup copy of your spellbook. This is just like copying a new spell into your spellbook, but faster and easier, since you understand your own notation and already know how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 10 gp for each level of the copied spell.
	If you lose your spellbook, you can use the same procedure to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new spellbook. Filling out the remainder of your spellbook requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this reason, many wizards keep backup spellbooks in a safe place.
	 
The Book’s Appearance:
	Your spellbook is a unique compilation of spells, with its own decorative flourishes and margin notes. It might be a plain, functional leather volume that you received as a gift from your master, a finely bound gilt-edged tome you found in an ancient library, or even a loose collection of notes scrounged together after you lost your previous spellbook in a mishap.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 114</text></feat><feat><name>Arcane Recovery</name><text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.
	For example, if you’re a 4th-level wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>2</level><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Tradition</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: Bladesinging</name><text>Bladesingers master a tradition of wizardry that incorporates swordplay and dance. Originally created by elves, this tradition has been adopted by non-elf practitioners, who honor and expand on the elven ways.

In combat, a bladesinger uses a series of intricate, elegant maneuvers that fend off harm and allow the bladesinger to channel magic into devastating attacks and a cunning defense. Many who have observed a bladesinger at work remember the display as one of the more beautiful experiences in their life, a glorious dance accompanied by a singing blade.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Training in War and Song (Bladesinging)</name><text>When you adopt this tradition at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with light armor, and you gain proficiency with one type of one-handed melee weapon of your choice.
	You also gain proficiency in the Performance skill if you don’t already have it.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 142</text><optional>1</optional><proficiency>112</proficiency></feat><feat><name>Bladesong (Bladesinging)</name><text>You can invoke an elven magic called the Bladesong, provided that you aren’t wearing medium or heavy armor or using a shield. It graces you with supernatural speed, agility, and focus.

You can use a bonus action to start the Bladesong, which lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are incapacitated, if you don medium or heavy armor or a shield, or if you use two hands to make an attack with a weapon. You can also dismiss the Bladesong at any time (no action required).

While your Bladesong is active, you gain the following benefits:

You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).
Your walking speed increases by 10 feet.
You have advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks.
You gain a bonus to any Constitution saving throw you make to maintain your concentration on a spell. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).
You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Abjuration</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Abjuration Savant (School of Abjuration)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an abjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Ward (School of Abjuration)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can weave magic around yourself for protection. When you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously use a strand of the spell’s magic to create a magical ward on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The ward has hit points equal to twice your wizard level + your Intelligence modifier. Whenever you take damage, the ward takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.
	While the ward has 0 hit points, it can’t absorb damage, but its magic remains. Whenever you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, the ward regains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the spell.
	Once you create the ward, you can’t create it again until you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Conjuration</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Conjuration Savant (School of Conjuration)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Minor Conjuration (School of Conjuration)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can use your action to conjure up an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet.
	The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, or if it takes or deals any damage.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Divination</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divination Savant (School of Divination)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a divination spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Portent (School of Divination)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness. When you finish a long rest, roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of these foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.
	Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Enchantment</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Enchantment Savant (School of Enchantment)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an enchantment spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Hypnotic Gaze (School of Enchantment)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, your soft words and enchanting gaze can magically enthrall another creature. As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 5 feet of you. If the target can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn. The charmed creature’s speed drops to 0, and the creature is incapacitated and visibly dazed.
	On subsequent turns, you can use your action to maintain this effect, extending its duration until the end of your next turn. However, the effect ends if you move more than 5 feet away from the creature, if the creature can neither see nor hear you, or if the creature takes damage.
	Once the effect ends, or if the creature succeeds on its initial saving throw against this effect, you can’t use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.
	 
Charmed:
• A charmed creature can&#39;t attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.
	 
Incapacitated:
• An incapacitated creature can&#39;t take actions or reactions.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Evocation</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Evocation Savant (School of Evocation)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Sculpt Spells (School of Evocation)</name><text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can create pockets of relative safety within the effects of your evocation spells. When you cast an evocation spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1+the spell’s level. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Illusion</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Illusion Savant (School of Illusion)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an illusion spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Minor Illusion (School of Illusion)</name><text>When you choose this school at 2nd level, you learn the minor illusion cantrip. If you already know this cantrip, you learn a different wizard cantrip of your choice. The cantrip doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known.
	When you cast minor illusion, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Necromancy</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Necromancy Savant (School of Necromancy)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Grim Harvest (School of Necromancy)</name><text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to reap life energy from creatures you kill with your spells. Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you regain hit points equal to twice the spell’s level, or three times its level if the spell belongs to the School of Necromancy. You don’t gain this benefit for killing constructs or undead.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: School of Transmutation</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.
	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Transmutation Savant (School of Transmutation)</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a transmutation spell into your spellbook is halved.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Minor Alchemy (School of Transmutation)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can temporarily alter the physical properties of one nonmagical object, changing it from one substance into another. You perform a special alchemical procedure on one object composed entirely of wood, stone (but not a gemstone), iron, copper, or silver, transforming it into a different one of those materials. For each 10 minutes you spend performing the procedure, you can transform up to 1 cubic foot of material. After 1 hour, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), the material reverts to its original substance.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: War Magic</name><text>A variety of arcane colleges specialize in training wizards for war. The tradition of War Magic blends principles of evocation and abjuration, rather than specializing in either of those schools. It teaches techniques that empower a caster’s spells, while also providing methods for a wizard to bolster their own defenses.
	Followers of this tradition are known as war mages. They see their magic as both a weapon and armor, a resource superior to any flimsy piece of steel. War mages act fast in battle, using their spells to seize tactical control of a situation. Their spells strike hard, while their defensive skills foil their opponents’ attempts to counterattack. War mages are also adept at turning other spellcasters’ magical energy against them.
	In great battles, a war mage often works with evokers, abjurers, and other types of wizards. Evokers, in particular, sometimes tease war mages for splitting their attention between offense and defense. A war mage’s typical response: "What good is being able to throw a mighty fireball if I die before I can cast it?"
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 59</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Deflection (War Magic)</name><text>At 2nd level, you have learned to weave your magic to fortify yourself against harm. When you are hit by an attack or fail a Constitution saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain a +2 bonus to your AC against that attack or a +4 bonus to that saving throw.
	When you use this feature, you can’t cast spells other than cantrips until the end of your next turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 59</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Tactical Wit (War Magic)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, your ability to quickly assess tactical situations allows you to act quickly in battle. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Intelligence modifier.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: Order Of Scribes</name><text>Magic of the book—that’s what many folk call wizardry. The name is apt, given how much time wizards spend poring over tomes and penning theories about the nature of magic. It’s rare to see wizards traveling without books and scrolls sprouting from their bags, and a wizard would go to great lengths to plumb an archive of ancient knowledge.

Among wizards, the Order of Scribes is the most bookish. It takes many forms in different worlds, but its primary mission is the same everywhere: recording magical discoveries so that wizardry can flourish. And while all wizards value spellbooks, a wizard in the Order of Scribes magically awakens their book, turning it into a trusted companion. All wizards study books, but a wizardly scribe talks to theirs!</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Wizardly Quill (Scribes)</name><text>As a bonus action, you can magically create a Tiny quill in your free hand. The magic quill has the following properties:

The quill doesn’t require ink. When you write with it, it produces ink in a color of your choice on the writing surface.
The time you must spend to copy a spell into your spellbook equals 2 minutes per spell level if you use the quill for the transcription.
You can erase anything you write with the quill if you wave the feather over the text as a bonus action, provided the text is within 5 feet of you.
This quill disappears if you create another one or if you die.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Awakened Spellbook (Scribes)</name><text>Using specially prepared inks and ancient incantations passed down by your wizardly order, you have awakened an arcane sentience within your spellbook.

While you are holding the book, it grants you the following benefits:

You can use the book as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells.
When you cast a wizard spell with a spell slot, you can temporarily replace its damage type with a type that appears in another spell in your spellbook, which magically alters the spell’s formula for this casting only. The latter spell must be of the same level as the spell slot you expend.
When you cast a wizard spell as a ritual, you can use the spell’s normal casting time, rather than adding 10 minutes to it. Once you use this benefit, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.
If necessary, you can replace the book over the course of a short rest by using your Wizardly Quill to write arcane sigils in a blank book or a magic spellbook to which you’re attuned. At the end of the rest, your spellbook’s consciousness is summoned into the new book, which the consciousness transforms into your spellbook, along with all its spells. If the previous book still existed somewhere, all the spells vanish from its pages.

</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: Chronurgy</name><text>Focusing on the manipulation of time, those who follow the Chronurgy tradition learn to alter the pace of reality to their liking. Using the ramping of anticipatory dunamis energy, these mages can bend the flow of time as adroitly as a skilled musician plays an instrument, lending themselves and their allies an advantage in the blink of an eye.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Chronal Shift (Chronurgy)</name><text>You can magically exert limited control over the flow of time around a creature. As a reaction, after you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can force the creature to reroll. You make this decision after you see whether the roll succeeds or fails. The target must use the result of the second roll.

You can use this ability twice, and you regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Temporal Awareness (Chronurgy)</name><text>You can add your Intelligence modifier to your initiative rolls.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: Graviturgy</name><text>Understanding and mastering the forces that draw bodies of matter together or drive them apart, the students of the Graviturgy arcane tradition learn to further bend and manipulate the violent energy of gravity to their benefit, and the terrible detriment of their enemies.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Adjust Density (Graviturgy)</name><text>As an action, you can magically alter the weight of one object or creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The object or creature must be Large or smaller. The target’s weight is halved or doubled for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell).

While the weight of a creature is halved by this effect, the creature’s speed increases by 10 feet, it can jump twice as far as normal, and it has disadvantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws. While the weight of a creature is doubled by this effect, the creature’s speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.

Upon reaching 10th level in this class, you can target an object or a creature that is Huge or smaller.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition: Witchcraft</name><text>Hidden away within enchanted forests and swamps are students of magic shunned and condemned by society, for they practice the taboo study of witchcraft: a collective of macabre magic developed to invoke terrible curses upon the helpless. Witches don’t just mark their victims with their hexes, but also they also weave their magic into brews and concoctions. Desperate souls sometimes seek out witches for their alchemic prowess, searching for a philter to charm their true love or a cure to a terrible disease. However, the few who do manage to meet a witch are often given a deadly poison in disguise.

Many practitioners of witchcraft are hags, although a few are outcasts who have been exiled for their malicious activities.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Baleful Hex (Witchcraft)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you learn how to mark someone with an ill fate. As a bonus action, you can target one creature you can see within 60 feet of you. The target is cursed for 1 minute. Until the curse ends, your attacks and spells deal extra necrotic damage to the target equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1 damage), and whenever the target makes an ability check or a saving throw, you can use your reaction to roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from the ability check or saving throw. The curse ends early if the target dies, you die, or you are incapacitated.

Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of any level to use it again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Exotic Brew (Witchcraft)</name><text>Also at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with herbalism kits. If you have an herbalism kit, you can spend two hours to craft an exotic potion, or one hour if you also have a cauldron. Crafting a potion this way requires 10 gp worth of materials and an exotic ingredient. Exotic ingredients are strange components only found in nature, such as frog legs or spider eyes, and you can find one exotic ingredient per hour spent foraging in the wilderness. Apothecaries and similar places may also have exotic ingredients for sale. When you create the potion, you choose the effect it has from one of the following options. 

Potions last indefinitely but you may only have as many crafted equal to your intelligence modifier, a minimum of 1. At 10th level it becomes your intelligence modifier plus 1. 

Additionally, when you create the potion, you can magically mask it as one of the other options on the table, such as making a poison potion appear as a healing potion. The mask is merely an illusion, and a creature who makes a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC determines its true nature.

Acid. As an action, a creature can spill this potion and make a melee attack roll against a target within 5 feet of them, or throw it and make a ranged attack roll against a target within 20 feet if they throw it. In either case, the creature adds their proficiency bonus and Dexterity modifier to the attack roll. On a hit, the target takes 2d6 acid damage. If the target is an object or surface made of wood or metal, the acid eats a hole through it 6 inches in diameter and 1 inch deep. A creature also takes this damage if they drink the potion.
The damage increases to 3d6 when you reach 10th level in this class.

Healing. The drinker regains a number of hit points equal to 2d4 + your Intelligence modifier. This potion has no effect on undead or constructs.
The healing increases to 3d4 + your Intelligence modifier when you reach 10th level in this class.

Love. The drinker is charmed for 1 hour by the next creature they see within 10 minutes of drinking it. The effect ends early if the subject of the creature’s charm or any of their companions do anything harmful to the drinker.
When you reach 10th level in this class, the duration of the charming effect increases to 8 hours.

Poison. The drinker takes 3d8 poison damage and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be poisoned. While poisoned this way, at the end of every minute the drinker takes an additional 1d8 poison damage and can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a successful save.
The initial damage increases to 4d8 when you reach 10th level in this class.

Resistance. The drinker gains resistance to one of the following damage types for 1 minute, chosen randomly: acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, thunder.
When you reach 10th level in this class, you can choose the damage type when you create the potion, instead of determining randomly.

Vitality. The drinker is cured of one disease or poison affecting it. This potion has no effect on undead or constructs.
When you reach 10th level in this class, the drinker’s exhaustion level is also reduced by one.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>3</level><slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Cantrip Formulas: Optional Feature</name><text>You have scribed a set of arcane formulas in your spellbook that you can use to formulate a cantrip in your mind. Whenever you finish a long rest and consult those formulas in your spellbook, you can replace one wizard cantrip you know with another cantrip from the wizard spell list.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>4</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>5</level><slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>6</level><slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Extra Attack (Bladesinging)</name><text>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn. Moreover, you can cast one of your cantrips in place of one of those attacks.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Projected Ward (School of Abjuration)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause your Arcane Ward to absorb that damage. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, the warded creature takes any remaining damage.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Benign Transposition (School of Conjuration)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your action to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Alternatively, you can choose a space within range that is occupied by a Small or Medium creature. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places.
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest or you cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Expert Divination (School of Divination)</name><text>Beginning at 6th level, casting divination spells comes so easily to you that it expends only a fraction of your spellcasting efforts. When you cast a divination spell of 2nd level or higher using a spell slot, you regain one expended spell slot. The slot you regain must be of a level lower than the spell you cast and can’t be higher than 5th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Instinctive Charm (School of Enchantment)</name><text>Beginning at 6th level, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to divert the attack, provided that another creature is within the attack’s range. The attacker must make a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker must target the creature that is closest to it, not including you or itself. If multiple creatures are closest, the attacker chooses which one to target. On a successful save, you can’t use this feature on the attacker again until you finish a long rest.
	You must choose to use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this effect.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Potent Cantrip (School of Evocation)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, your damaging cantrips affect even creatures that avoid the brunt of the effect. When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip’s damage (if any) but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Malleable Illusions (School of Illusion)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast an illusion spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can use your action to change the nature of that illusion (using the spell’s normal parameters for the illusion), provided that you can see the illusion.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Undead Thralls (School of Necromancy)</name><text>At 6th level, you add the animate dead spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. When you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton, as appropriate.
	Whenever you create an undead using a necromancy spell, it has additional benefits.
	 
• The creature’s hit point maximum is increased by an amount equal to your wizard level.
	 
• The creature adds your proficiency bonus to its weapon damage rolls.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Transmuter&#39;s Stone (School of Transmutation)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can spend 8 hours creating a transmuter’s stone that stores transmutation magic. You can benefit from the stone yourself or give it to another creature. A creature gains a benefit of your choice as long as the stone is in the creature’s possession. When you create the stone, choose the benefit from the following options.
	 
• Darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, as described in chapter 8
	 
• An increase to speed of 10 feet while the creature is unencumbered
	 
• Proficiency in Constitution saving throws
	 
• Resistance to acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage (your choice whenever you choose this benefit).
	 
	Each time you cast a transmutation spell of 1st level or higher, you can change the effect of your stone if the stone is on your person.
	If you create a new transmuter’s stone, the previous one ceases to function.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Power Surge (War Magic)</name><text>Starting at 6th level,you can store magical energy within yourself to later empower your damaging spells. In its stored form, this energy is called a power surge.
	You can store a maximum number of power surges equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one). Whenever you finish a long rest, your number of power surges resets to one. Whenever you successfully end a spell with dispel magic or counterspell, you gain one power surge, as you steal magic from the spell you foiled. If you end a short rest with no power surges, you gain one power surge.
	Once per turn when you deal damage to a creature or object with a wizard spell, you can spend one power surge to deal extra force damage to that target. The extra damage equals half your wizard level.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Manifest Mind (Scribes)</name><text>You can conjure forth the mind of your Awakened Spellbook. As a bonus action while the book is on your person, you can cause the mind to manifest as a Tiny spectral object, hovering in an unoccupied space of your choice within 60 feet of you. The spectral mind is intangible and doesn’t occupy its space, and it sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. It looks like a ghostly tome, a cascade of text, or a scholar from the past (your choice).

While manifested, the spectral mind can hear and see, and it has darkvision with a range of 60 feet. The mind can telepathically share with you what it sees and hears (no action required).

Whenever you cast a wizard spell on your turn, you can cast it as if you were in the spectral mind’s space, instead of your own, using its senses. You can do so a number of times per day equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

As a bonus action, you can cause the spectral mind to hover up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you or it can see. It can pass through creatures but not objects.

The spectral mind stops manifesting if it is ever more than 300 feet away from you, if someone casts dispel magic on it, if the Awakened Spellbook is destroyed, if you die, or if you dismiss the spectral mind as a bonus action.

Once you conjure the mind, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest, unless you expend a spell slot of any level to conjure it again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Momentary Stasis (Chronurgy)</name><text>As an action, you can magically force a Large or smaller creature you can see within 60 feet of you to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. Unless the saving throw is a success, the creature is encased in a field of magical energy until the end of your next turn or until the creature takes any damage. While encased in this way, the creature is incapacitated and has a speed of 0.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Gravity Well (Graviturgy)</name><text>You’ve learned how to manipulate gravity around a living being: whenever you cast a spell on a creature, you can move the target 5 feet to an unoccupied space of your choice if the target is willing to move, the spell hits it with an attack, or it fails a saving throw against the spell.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Manic Malediction (Witchcraft)</name><text>At 6th level, you add the bestow curse spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. For you, it has a range of 30 feet, and you can cast it as a bonus action. When you cast bestow curse, the nature of the curse can be one of the following additional options:

The target begins vividly hallucinating. While the target is cursed, it has disadvantage on all ability checks.
The target hears constant screaming in its head. While cursed, the target is deafened, can’t concentrate on spells, and takes 1d4 psychic damage at the start of each of its turns. This damage can’t reduce the target’s hit points below 10.
While cursed, the target can only speak gibberish, and is incapable of normal speech or casting spells that require a verbal component.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>7</level><slots>3,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>8</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>3,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>9</level><slots>3,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>10</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Song of Defense (Bladesinging)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, you can direct your magic to absorb damage while your bladesong is active. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to expend one spell slot and reduce that damage to you by an amount equal to five times the spell’s slot level.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 142</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Abjuration (School of Abjuration)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, when you cast an abjuration spell that requires you to make an ability check as a part of casting that spell (as in counterspell and dispel magic), you add your proficiency bonus to that ability check.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Focused Conjuration (School of Conjuration)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken as a result of taking damage.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>The Third Eye (School of Divination)</name><text>Starting at 10th level, you can use your action to increase your powers of perception. When you do so, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated or you take a short or long rest. You can’t use the feature again until you finish a rest.
	 
Darkvision:
	You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, as described in chapter 8. 
	 
Ethereal Sight:
	You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you. 
	 
Greater Comprehension:
	You can read any language. 
	 
See Invisibility:
	You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Split Enchantment (School of Enchantment)</name><text>Starting at 10th level, when you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher that targets only one creature, you can have it target a second creature.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Empowered Evocation (School of Evocation)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, you can add your Intelligence modifier to one damage roll of any wizard evocation spell you cast.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Illusory Step (School of Illusion)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, you can create an illusory duplicate of yourself as an instant, almost instinctual reaction to danger. When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to interpose the illusory duplicate between the attacker and yourself. The attack automatically misses you, then the illusion dissipates.
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Inured to Undeath (School of Necromancy)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, you have resistance to necrotic damage, and your hit point maximum can’t be reduced. You have spent so much time dealing with undead and the forces that animate them that you have become inured to some of their worst effects.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Shapechanger (School of Transmutation)</name><text>At 10th level, you add the polymorph spell to your spellbook, if it is not there already. You can cast polymorph without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can target only yourself and transform into a beast whose challenge rating is 1 or lower.
	Once you cast polymorph in this way, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, though you can still cast it normally using an available spell slot.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Durable Magic (War Magic)</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, the magic you channel helps ward off harm. While you maintain concentration on a spell, you have a +2 bonus to AC and all saving throws.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master Scrivener (Scribes)</name><text>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can create one magic scroll by touching your Wizardly Quill to a blank piece of paper or parchment and causing one spell from your Awakened Spellbook to be copied onto the scroll. The spellbook must be within 5 feet of you when you make the scroll.

The chosen spell must be of 1st or 2nd level and must have a casting time of 1 action. Once in the scroll, the spell’s power is enhanced, counting as one level higher than normal. You can cast the spell from the scroll by reading it as an action. The scroll is unintelligible to anyone else, and the spell vanishes from the scroll when you cast it or when you finish your next long rest.

You are also adept at crafting spell scrolls, which are described in the treasure chapter of the Dungeon Master’s Guide. The gold and time you must spend to make such a scroll are halved if you use your Wizardly Quill.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Abeyance (Chronurgy)</name><text>When you cast a spell using a spell slot of 4th level or lower, you can condense the spell’s magic into a mote. The spell is frozen in time at the moment of casting and held within a gray bead for 1 hour. This bead is a Tiny object with AC 15 and 1 hit point, and it is immune to poison and psychic damage. When the duration ends, or if the bead is destroyed, it vanishes in a flash of light, and the spell is lost.

A creature holding the bead can use its action to release the spell within, whereupon the bead disappears. The spell uses your spell attack bonus and save DC, and the spell treats the creature who released it as the caster for all other purposes.

Once you create a bead with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Violent Attraction (Graviturgy)</name><text>When another creature that you can see within 60 feet of you hits with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to increase the attack’s velocity, causing the attack’s target to take an extra 1d10 damage of the weapon’s type.

Alternatively, if a creature within 60 feet of you takes damage from a fall, you can use your reaction to increase the fall’s damage by 2d10.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Accursed Condition (Witchcraft)</name><text>At 10th level, you can imbue your potions with dreadful magic. As an action, you can touch one of your exotic potions and expend a spell slot of 4th-level or higher to store one of the following curses in it:

The drinker suffers the effects of one of the curses you can create with bestow curse.

The drinker suffers effects of the polymorph spell, transforming into a beast of your choice whose challenge rating is 1 or lower, but they retain their mental ability scores, personality, and alignment.

The drinker is under the effect of the feign death spell.

The stored curse triggers when a creature drinks the potion. The drinker must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be afflicted with the stored curse for 12 hours. It has disadvantage on this saving throw if the potion is masked and the drinker isn’t aware of it. If you expended a spell slot of 5th-level or higher, the duration increases by 12 hours for each slot level above 4th. As an action, you can touch a creature afflicted with a stored curse and dismiss the effect. A remove curse spell ends the effect early.

You can only store one curse at a time. The curse remains in the potion until the potion is consumed or you use this feature again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>11</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>12</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>13</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>14</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Song of Victory (Bladesinging)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, you add your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage of your melee weapon attacks while your Bladesong is active.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 142</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spell Resistance (School of Abjuration)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, you have advantage on saving throws against spells.
	Furthermore, you have resistance against the damage of spells.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Durable Summons (School of Conjuration)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 116</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Greater Portent (School of Divination)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, the visions in your dreams intensify and paint a more accurate picture in your mind of what is to come. You roll three d20s for your Portent feature, rather than two.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Alter Memories (School of Enchantment)</name><text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to make a creature unaware of your magical influence on it. When you cast an enchantment spell to charm one or more creatures, you can alter one creature’s understanding so that it remains unaware of being charmed.
	Additionally, once before the spell expires, you can use your action to try to make the chosen creature forget some of the time it spent charmed. The creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or lose a number of hours of its memories equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can make the creature forget less time, and the amount of time can’t exceed the duration of your enchantment spell.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 117</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Overchannel (School of Evocation)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, you can increase the power of your simpler spells. When you cast a wizard spell of 1st through 5th level that deals damage, you can deal maximum damage with that spell.
	The first time you do so, you suffer no adverse effect. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Illusory Reality (School of Illusion)</name><text>By 14th level, you have learned the secret of weaving shadow magic into your illusions to give them a semireality. When you cast an illusion spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose one inanimate, nonmagical object that is part of the illusion and make that object real. You can do this on your turn as a bonus action while the spell is ongoing. The object remains real for 1 minute. For example, you can create an illusion of a bridge over a chasm and then make it real long enough for your allies to cross.
	The object can’t deal damage or otherwise directly harm anyone.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 118</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Command Undead (School of Necromancy)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, you can use magic to bring undead under your control, even those created by other wizards. As an action, you can choose one undead that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Charisma saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. If it succeeds, you can’t use this feature on it again. If it fails, it becomes friendly to you and obeys your commands until you use this feature again.
	Intelligent undead are harder to control in this way. If the target has an Intelligence of 8 or higher, it has advantage on the saving throw. If it fails the saving throw and has an Intelligence of 12 or higher, it can repeat the saving throw at the end of every hour until it succeeds and breaks free.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master Transmuter (School of Transmutation)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, you can use your action to consume the reserve of transmutation magic stored within your transmuter’s stone in a single burst. When you do so, choose one of the following effects. Your transmuter’s stone is destroyed and can’t be remade until you finish a long rest. 
	 
Major Transformation:
	You can transmute one nonmagical object — no larger than a 5-foot cube — into another nonmagical object of similar size and mass and of equal or lesser value. You must spend 10 minutes handling the object to transform it. 
	 
Panacea:
	You remove all curses, diseases, and poisons affecting a creature that you touch with the transmuter’s stone. The creature also regains all its hit points. 
	 
Restore Life:
	You cast the raise dead spell on a creature you touch with the transmuter’s stone, without expending a spell slot or needing to have the spell in your spellbook. 
	 
Restore Youth: 
	You touch the transmuter’s stone to a willing creature, and that creature’s apparent age is reduced by 3d10 years, to a minimum of 13 years. This effect doesn’t extend the creature’s lifespan.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 119</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Deflecting Shroud (War Magic)</name><text>At 14th level, your Arcane Deflection becomes infused with deadly magic. When you use your Arcane Deflection feature, you can cause magical energy to arc from you. Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you each take force damage equal to half your wizard level.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>One With The Word (Scribes)</name><text>Your connection to your Awakened Spellbook has become so profound that your soul has become entwined with it. While the book is on your person, you have advantage on all Intelligence (Arcana) checks, as the spellbook helps you remember magical lore.

Moreover, if you take damage while your spellbook’s mind is manifested, you can prevent all of that damage to you by using your reaction to dismiss the spectral mind, using its magic to save yourself. Then roll 3d6. The spellbook temporarily loses spells of your choice that have a combined spell level equal to that roll or higher. For example, if the roll’s total is 9, spells vanish from the book that have a combined level of at least 9, which could mean one 9th-level spell, three 3rd-level spells, or some other combination. If there aren’t enough spells in the book to cover this cost, you drop to 0 hit points.

Until you finish 1d6 long rests, you are incapable of casting the lost spells, even if you find them on a scroll or in another spellbook. After you finish the required number of rests, the spells reappear in the spellbook.

Once you use this reaction, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Convergent Future (Chronurgy)</name><text>You can peer through possible futures and magically pull one of them into events around you, ensuring a particular outcome. When you or a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction to ignore the die roll and decide whether the number rolled is the minimum needed to succeed or one less than that number (your choice).

When you use this feature, you gain one level of exhaustion. Only by finishing a long rest can you remove a level of exhaustion gained in this way.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Event Horizon (Graviturgy)</name><text>As an action, you can magically emit a powerful field of gravitational energy that tugs at other creatures for up to 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). For the duration, whenever a creature hostile to you starts its turn within 30 feet of you, it must make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, it takes 2d10 force damage, and its speed is reduced to 0 until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage, and every foot it moves this turn costs 2 extra feet of movement.

Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of 3rd level or higher on it.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Witching Hour (Witchcraft)</name><text>Starting at 14th level, your curses grow stronger:

When the target of your Baleful Hex drops to 0 hit points, you can move the curse to a different creature you can see within 60 feet of you, provided you aren’t incapacitated.

You don’t need to concentrate on bestow curse.

Any spell that would end a curse of yours early automatically fails if that spell is of a lower level than the spell slot you expended for the curse. For the purposes of this, a “curse” refers to any spell you can cast that can be ended with remove curse, as well as a curse created by your Accursed Concoction feature.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>15</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>16</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>17</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>18</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Spell Mastery</name><text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.
	By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>19</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>20</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Signature Spell</name><text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don’t count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
	If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 115</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><spellAbility>3</spellAbility><spell><name>Absorb Elements</name><school>1</school><level>1</level><time>1 reaction, which you take when you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage</time><range>Self</range><s>1</s><duration>1 round</duration><text>The spell captures some of the incoming energy, lessening its effect on you and storing it for your next melee attack. You have resistance to the triggering damage type until the start of your next turn. Also, the first time you hit with a melee attack on your next turn, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage of the triggering type, and the spell ends.
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 150^Elemental Evil Player&#39;s Companion, p. 15^Princes of the Apocalypse, p. 233</text><roll>1d6</roll><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Ranger</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Comprehend Languages</name><school>3</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a pinch of soot and salt</materials><duration>1 hour</duration><text>For the duration, you understand the literal meaning of any spoken language that you hear. You also understand any spoken language that you hear. You also understand any written language that you see, but you must be touching the surface on which the words are written. It takes about 1 minute to read one page of text. 
	This spell doesn&#39;t decode secret messages in a text or glyph, such as an arcane sigil, that isn&#39;t part of a written language. 

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 224</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Dancing Lights</name><school>5</school><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>You create up to four torch-sized lights within range, making them appear as torches, lanterns, or glowing orbs that hover in the air for the duration. You can also combine the four lights into one glowing vaguely humanoid form of Medium size. Whichever form you choose, each light sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. 
	As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the lights up to 60 feet to a new spot within range. A light must be within 20 feet of another light created by this spell, and a light winks out if it exceeds the spell&#39;s range.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 230</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Spellbinder</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Fire Bolt</name><school>5</school><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You hurl a mote of fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 fire damage. A flammable object hit by this spell ignites if it isn&#39;t being worn or carried. 
	This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 242</text><roll>1d10</roll><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Identify</name><school>3</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 minute</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a pearl worth at least 100 gp and an owl feather</materials><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You choose one object that you must touch throughout the casting of the spell. If it is a magic item or some other magic-imbued object, you learn its properties and how to use them, whether it requires attunement to use, and how many charges it has, if any. You learn whether any spells are affecting the item and what they are. If the item was created by a spell, you learn which spell created it. 
	If you instead touch a creature throughout the casting, you learn what spells, if any, are currently affecting it.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 252</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Spellbinder</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Mage Armor</name><school>1</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a piece of cured leather</materials><duration>8 hours</duration><text>You touch a willing creature who isn&#39;t wearing armor, and a protective magical force surrounds it until the spell ends. The target&#39;s base AC becomes 13+its Dexterity modifier. The spell ends it if the target dons armor or if you dismiss the spell as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 256</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (Witchcraft)</sclass><sclass>Witch</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Magic Missile</name><school>5</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You create three glowing darts of magical force. Each dart hits a creature of your choice that you can see within range. A dart deals 1d4+1 force damage to its target. The darts all strike simultaneously and you can direct them to hit one creature or several. 
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell creates one more dart for each slot above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 257</text><roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Warmage (Bishops)</sclass><sclass>Soul Binder</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Mind Sliver</name><school>4</school><time>1 action </time><range>60 feet</range><v>1</v><duration>1 round </duration><text>You drive a disorienting spike of psychic energy into the mind of one creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or take 1d6 psychic damage and subtract 1d4 from the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn.

This spell’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach certain levels: 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Thunderwave</name><school>5</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self (15-foot cube)</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn&#39;t pushed. 
	In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell&#39;s effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet. 
	
At Higher Levels: 
	When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 282</text><roll>2d8</roll><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Warmage (Bishops)</sclass><sclass>Warden</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell></class><container><name>Scholar’s Pack</name><text>Includes a backpack, a book of lore, a bottle of ink, an ink pen, 10 sheets of parchment, a little bag of sand, and a small knife.</text><value>40.0</value><item><name>Backpack</name><value>2.0</value><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Book of Lore</name><text>A book might contain poetry, historical accounts, information pertaining to a particular field of lore, diagrams and notes on gnomish contraptions, or just about anything else that can be represented using text or pictures. A book of spells is a spellbook (described later in this section).</text><value>25.0</value><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Ink (1 ounce bottle)</name><value>10.0</value></item><item><name>Ink pen</name><value>0.02</value></item><item><name>Parchment (one sheet)</name><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.1</value></item><item><name>Bag of Sand</name></item><item><name>Small Knife</name></item></container>
<item><name>Dagger</name><text>Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>5</type><slot>2</slot><quantity>2</quantity><value>2.0</value><weight>1.0</weight><damage1H>1d4</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty><weaponRange>20</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Gold (gp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>46</quantity><value>1.0</value><weight>0.02</weight></item><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><money>46.0</money></character>
</pc>