<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BwDTTM3IwwwlUHRFN0l4V3pITVE/view -->
<compendium version="5">
	<class>
	<name>Witcher</name>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<Proficiency>Constitution, Intelligence</Proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<autolevel level="1"> <slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2"> <slots>1,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
		<feature>
			<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Armor: none</text>
			<text>Weapons: Longswords, simple weapons, Hand Crossbow</text>
			<text>Tools: none</text>
			<text>Saving Throws: Constitution, Intelligence</text>
			<text>Skills: Choose two from Insight, Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, Persuasion and Survival.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Starting Equipment</name>
			<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background.</text>
			<text />
			<text>• (a) two longswords, or (b) a greataxe (if proficient) or (c) two shortswords (if proficient).</text>
			<text />
			<text>• (a) Leather armor (if proficient) or (b) scale mail (if proficient) or (c) chain mail (if proficient)</text>
			<text />
			<text>• (a) a hand crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two daggers</text>
			<text />
			<text>• An explorer's pack</text>
			<text />
			<text>• A blank bestiary and a metal witcher's medallion.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Witcher School</name>
			<text>Graduating from one of the five Witcher schools has taught you to fight in their particular style. Pick one from the list later in the class description, you gain bonuses from it at 1st, 3rd, 7th, 10th, and 17th level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Beastiary</name>
			<text>Your training in the ways of hunting monsters has made you an expert in recording and extrapolating data about the habits and lifestyle of many monsters, as well as the knowledge regarding how to fight them. After you kill a Monster, you may take 5 minutes and record it in your bestiary within the next 6 hours, and for all future encounters against that species of enemy (e.g. Griffon, not Monstrosity) in which you possess the bestiary, you may see into its weaknesses. You learn its damage immunities, resistances, as well as damage vulnerabilities.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Medallion</name>
			<text>During each witcher's training, they receive a medallion which represents the beast of their school, which trembles when Monsters are around you. While you have your medallion with you and there are Monsters within 100 feet of you that you cannot see, make a DC 10 perception check. On a sucess, you notice the medallion is shaking, alerting you to their presence, but not number, type, size or exact location.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">
		<feature>
			<name>Signs</name>
			<text>When you reach 2nd level you learn five spells specific to the witcher class, which use sign points rather than spell slots to cast. All only use somatic components. You may only cast the enhanced version of a sign if it is specifically outlined in your school description. Casting an enhanced version costs 2 sign points.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature>
			<name>Witcher School</name>
			<text>Graduating from one of the five Witcher schools has taught you to fight in their particular style. Pick one from the list later in the class description, you gain bonuses from it at 1st, 3rd, 7th, 10th, and 17th level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>School of the Wolf</name>
			<text>Witchers of the school of the wolf excel at adaptability. They are resourceful warriors, always preparing before they engage in combat, and this allows them to defeat enemies much stronger than themselves.</text>
			<text>When you choose this school at first level, you gain proficiency in Athletics, Medium Armor, and Longswords now count as finesse weapons.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>School of the Wolf: Improvised Arcana</name>
			<text>Starting at 3rd level, your versatility has expanded to include signs. You learn one enhanced version of a sign, but it costs 2 sign points to use. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you may change your enhanced sign out with another one.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>School of the Wolf: Versatile Alchemist</name>
			<text>Starting at 7th level, you have picked up some of the tricks of alchemy. You learn how to craft two enhanced versions of potions you already know. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you may exchange one of your enhanced potion formulas for another one you already know.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>School of the Wolf: Bombslinger</name>
			<text>Starting at 10th level, you may throw a bomb as a bonus action. In addition, you may carry an extra bomb with you. If you have access to a tinker's kit while making the bombs and you are proficient, you may increase or decrease the explosive range of the bombs by 5 feet. You may also throw bombs accurately up to 40 feet away from you.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>School of the Wolf: Adaptable</name>
			<text>Starting at 17th level, you have unlocked a new understanding of adapting to face your enemies. After you take damage from an enemy attack, you may use your action to become resistant to that type of damage for up to 5 minutes. You must finish a long rest before you can use this ability again. You also gain the ability to choose what type of damage a longsword you are wielding deals, choosing between Slashing, Bludgeoning or Piercing. You choose the damage type after you make the attack roll, but before the Dungeon Master declares a hit or miss. If you do not state the type, it deals slashing damage.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>School of the Cat</name>
			<text>The teachings of the School of the Cat focus on two things. Precision and Speed. As a result, they produce swift and deadly fighters capable of whirling through masses of enemies in seconds.</text>
			<text>When you choose this school at first level, you gain proficiency in Acrobatics, light armor, rapiers, and longswords count as finesse weapons.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Bombs</name>
			<text>Starting at 3rd level, you have learned how to make witcher’s bombs, small explosives that can affect your enemies in a multitude of ways. You may craft bombs during a short or long rest. You may only possess a number of bombs equal to your proficiency bonus at one time, and may not have more than 3 of the same type at any time. Each crafting of a bomb provides up to 3 bombs.</text>
			<text>At second level, you know 1 bomb formula from the list at the end of the class description, and each time you level up, you may select one of your known bomb formula and replace it with one you don’t know. Throwing a bomb takes an action, and you may throw any bomb accurately towards a spot within 35 feet of you.</text>
			<text>Some bombs make use of saving throws, your Bomb Save DC is 8 + your Intelligence Modifier + your proficiency bonus.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
	</autolevel>
</class>
</compendium>
