<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5"><character><version>37</version><uid>8823</uid><name>Thor Lvl5</name><abilities>15,10,14,10,13,10,</abilities><hpMax>49</hpMax><hpCurrent>49</hpCurrent><unarmed>1</unarmed><race><name>Protector Aasimar</name><feat><name>Darkvision</name><text>Blessed with a radiant soul, your vision can easily cut through darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can&#39;t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.
 
Source: Volo&#39;s Guide to Monsters, p. 105</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Celestial Resistance</name><text>You have resistance to necrotic damage and radiant damage.
 
Source: Volo&#39;s Guide to Monsters, p. 105</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Healing Hands</name><text>As an action, you can touch a creature and cause it to regain a number of hit points equal to your level. Once you use this trait, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a long rest.
 
Source: Volo&#39;s Guide to Monsters, p. 105</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Light Bearer</name><text>You know the light cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it.
 
Source: Volo&#39;s Guide to Monsters, p. 105</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Languages</name><text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Celestial.
 
Source: Volo&#39;s Guide to Monsters, p. 105</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Radiant Soul</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash the divine energy within yourself, causing your eyes to glimmer and two luminous, incorporeal wings to sprout from your back.
	Your transformation lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action.. During it, you have a flying speed of 30 feet, and once on each of your turns, you can deal extra radiant damageto one target when you deal damage to it with an attack or a spell. The extra radiant damage equals your level.
	Once you use this trait, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a long rest.
 
Source: Volo&#39;s Guide to Monsters, p. 105</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><mod><category>1</category><type>4</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><category>1</category><type>5</type><value>2</value></mod><spellAbility>5</spellAbility><spell><name>Light</name><school>5</school><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><m>1</m><materials>a firefly or phosphorescent moss</materials><duration>1 hour</duration><text>You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again or dismiss it as an action. 
	If you target an object held or worn by a hostile creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 255</text><prepared>1</prepared><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Spellbinder</sclass><sclass>Soul Binder</sclass></spell></race><background><name>Fallen Noble</name><feat><name>Description</name><text>You were once the member of a powerful noble family. Perhaps you were from a well-known merchant family, or you came from a line of wealthy aristocrats. However, due to events beyond your control―or perhaps they were―, you or your family have fallen from grace. Maybe your family was outcast from the kingdom with their property stripped away after one of the family members committed an unforgivable crime, or they were attacked and killed by angry mobs, with you being the sole survivor. Perhaps you were disowned for not following family tradition, or left of your own accord, not wanting to be bound by the fate your parents had set for you. Work with your DM to find out your family&#39;s role and how their role and downfall affected the world in your campaign.
Whatever the reasoning, you were of noble birth, yet your family is no longer considered noble. You have been forced to make a new life for yourself and adjust to life without servants at your command and money at your disposal. Will you attempt to reclaim your title or move away from it? Will you shout your true identity from the rooftops hoping someone will believe you, or keep it a secret from everyone but your closest allies for fear of being accused as a liar? It&#39;s all up to you.
</text></feat><feat><name>Starting Proficiencies</name><text>Skill Proficiencies: History and Persuasion or Deception

Tool Proficiencies: One type of gaming set or musical instrument

Languages: One of your choice</text></feat><feat><name>Starting Equipment</name><text>Equipment: A set of common clothes, a trinket from your family (statuette, music box, etc.), a warm blanket, and a pouch containing 15 gp</text></feat><feat><name>Downfall Of The Powerful</name><text>Your family was once wealthy and powerful, but something caused you to lose everything. What happened? Was it something out of your control, or did you have a part in it? Was your own family to blame? Or perhaps another noble family wanting to take you down? Discuss with your DM what caused your downfall or roll a d8 and choose from the table below.

d6	Downfall of the Powerful
1	Someone in my family committed a heinous crime, resulting in our power being stripped away.
2	My family was killed by an angry mob. I was the only survivor.
3	I refused to follow family tradition or what my parents wanted for me and was disowned for it.
4	I was accused of a crime. Whether or not I was guilty, rumors began to spread, eventually causing my fall from grace.
5	Another noble family tore mine apart through lies, deceit, and sabotage.
6	A high-ranking member of my family was killed and everything slowly fell apart.
</text></feat><feat><name>Feature: Insider Knowledge</name><text>You know exactly who to talk to in order to find out gossip, hidden secrets, or any other information about various noble families. This information could come from members of the family in question, servants who work for them, other people who either know them personally, or those who may have eavesdropped on their conversations. Not everyone is willing to reveal such private information, though― if the person believes they may be put in a dangerous situation by revealing the information you request, they will not tell you or may even lie to protect themselves.
</text></feat><feat><name>Personality Traits</name><text>d8	Personality Trait
1	I still demand others to treat me as they would any other noble.
2	I don’t like getting my hands dirty, and often make others do the dirty work.
3	I&#39;ll tell anybody I&#39;m from a noble family, even random strangers. They have to know!
4	I can&#39;t let anybody but those I trust the most know of my noble birth.
5	Despite my noble birth, I do not consider myself superior to others. We are all the same in the end.
6	I strive to make up for my family&#39;s horrible behavior in whatever way I can.
7	I&#39;ll be fine even in the simplest conditions. Anything is better than nothing.
8	Despite my noble birth, I act more like a commoner.</text></feat><feat><name>Ideal</name><text>d6	Ideal
1	Sympathy. I know what it&#39;s like to have nothing, and I wish to help those who are less fortunate. (Good)
2	Power.I want to reclaim my noble status by any means necessary. (Chaotic)
3	Revenge. I&#39;ll make those who caused my fall from grace pay for what they did. (Evil)
4	Moving forward. I want to leave my old life behind and start anew. (Lawful)
5	My allies. The blood of the covenant is thicker than the water of the womb. (Any)
6	Redemption. I want to make up for what my family did, and protect others from those who abuse their power. (Good)
</text></feat><feat><name>Bond</name><text>d6	Bond
1	A lower-class family helped me when I was at my lowest. I want to repay them in whatever way I can.
2	I strive to leave my old alliances behind and forge new friendships.
3	When I left my old life behind, I also left an old friend behind. I wish to see them again.
4	I still hold some loyalty to my former family.
5	I wish to make up for my family&#39;s misdeeds.
6	I want to regain my status and restore my family&#39;s honor.</text></feat><feat><name>Flaw</name><text>d6	Flaw
1	I&#39;m often paranoid that my allies will discover my noble birth and call me a traitor.
2	I&#39;ll do anything to regain the power I lost, even if it means throwing my allies under the cart.
3	I feel responsible for what my family did, even though I had no part in it.
4	I&#39;ll do anything to hide my past identity. Nobody can know who I used to be.
5	Even though I no longer hold the title, I still act like I&#39;m a noble.
6	Despite my fall from grace, I still see myself as superior to others. This often gets me in trouble.</text></feat></background><class><name>Fighter</name><level>3</level><hdCurrent>3</hdCurrent><hd>3</hd><wealth>5d4x10</wealth><slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><proficiency>0</proficiency><proficiency>2</proficiency><proficiency>100</proficiency><proficiency>103</proficiency><numClassSkills>2</numClassSkills><armor>light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields</armor><weapons>simple weapons, martial weapons</weapons><tools>none</tools><feat><name>Starting Fighter</name><text>As a 1st-level Fighter, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields
• Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
• Tools: none
• Skills: Choose two skills from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, and Survival
 
You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) chain mail or (b) leather, longbow, and 20 arrows
• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons
• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes
• (a) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack 
 
Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 70</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Second Wind</name><text>You have a limited well of stamina that you can draw on to protect yourself from harm. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d10 + your fighter level.
	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style</name><text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Great Weapon Fighting, Mariner, Protection, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name><text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>2</special></feat><feat><name>Action Surge</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can push yourself beyond your normal limits for a moment. On your turn, you can take one additional action on top of your regular action and a possible bonus action.
	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 17th level, you can use it twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype</name><text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your combat styles and techniques. Choose Champion, Battle Master, or Eldritch Knight, all detailed at the end of the class description. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Eldritch Knight</name><text>The archetypal Eldritch Knight combines the martial mastery common to all fighters with a careful study of magic. Eldritch Knights use magical techniques similar to those practiced by wizards. They focus their study on two of the eight schools of magic: abjuration and evocation. Abjuration spells grant an Eldritch Knight additional protection in battle, and evocation spells deal damage to many foes at once, extending the fighter’s reach in combat. These knights learn a comparatively small number of spells, committing them to memory instead of keeping them in a spellbook.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 74</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>When you reach 3rd level, you augment your martial prowess with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. 
	 
Cantrips: You learn two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level. 
	 
Spell Slots: The Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. 
	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell shield and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast shield using either slot. 
	 
Spells Known of 1st-level and Higher: You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the abjuration and evocation spells on the wizard spell list.
	The Spells Known column of the Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows when you learn more wizard spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be an abjuration or evocation spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
	The spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic.
	Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an abjuration or evocation spell, unless you’re replacing the spell you gained at 3rd, 8th, 14th, or 20th level from any school of magic. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability: Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. 
	 
Spell save DC = 8+your proficiency bonus+your Intelligence modifier 
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus+your Intelligence modifier
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Weapon Bond (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>At 3rd level, you learn a ritual that creates a magical bond between yourself and one weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual, at the conclusion of which you touch the weapon and forge the bond.
	Once you have bonded a weapon to yourself, you can’t be disarmed of that weapon unless you are incapacitated. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand.
	You can have up to two bonded weapons, but can summon only one at a time with your bonus action. If you attempt to bond with a third weapon, you must break the bond with one of the other two.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><autolevel><slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Starting Fighter</name><text>As a 1st-level Fighter, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields
• Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
• Tools: none
• Skills: Choose two skills from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, and Survival
 
You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) chain mail or (b) leather, longbow, and 20 arrows
• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons
• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes
• (a) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack 
 
Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 70</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Multiclass Fighter</name><text>To multiclass as a Fighter, you must meet the following prerequisites:
• Strength 13 or Dexterity 13
 
You gain the following proficiencies:
• light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 163</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Second Wind</name><text>You have a limited well of stamina that you can draw on to protect yourself from harm. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d10 + your fighter level.
	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style</name><text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Great Weapon Fighting, Mariner, Protection, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Archery</name><text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>0</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Blind Fighting</name><text>You have blindsight with a range of 10 feet. Within that range, you can effectively see anything that isn’t behind total cover, even if you’re blinded or in darkness. Moreover, you can see an invisible creature within that range, unless the creature successfully hides from you.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Protection</name><text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter</name><text>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional><mod><type>5</type><value>1</value></mod></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Defense</name><text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>1</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name><text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>2</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Interception</name><text>When a creature you can see hits a target, other than you, within 5 feet of you with an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + your proficiency bonus (to a minimum of 0 damage). You must be wielding a shield or a simple or martial weapon to use this reaction. </text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name><text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name><text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Superior Technique</name><text>You learn one maneuver of your choice from among those available to the Battle Master archetype. If a maneuver you use requires your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver’s effects, the saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).

You gain one superiority die, which is a d6 (this die is added to any superiority dice you have from another source). This die is used to fuel your maneuvers. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter</name><text>You excel at defending narrow passages, doorways, and other tight spaces. As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Thrown Weapon</name><text>You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon.

In addition, when you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +2 bonus to the damage roll.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name><text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Unarmed</name><text>Your unarmed strikes can deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier on a hit. If you aren’t wielding any weapons or a shield when you make the attack roll, the d6 becomes a d8.

At the start of each of your turns, you can deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage to one creature grappled by you.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>2</level><slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Action Surge</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can push yourself beyond your normal limits for a moment. On your turn, you can take one additional action on top of your regular action and a possible bonus action.
	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 17th level, you can use it twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>3</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Martial Archetype</name><text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your combat styles and techniques. Choose Champion, Battle Master, or Eldritch Knight, all detailed at the end of the class description. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Arcane Archer</name><text>An Arcane Archer studies a unique elven method of archery that weaves magic into attacks to produce supernatural effects. Arcane Archers are some of their most elite warriors among the elves. They stand watch over the fringes of elven domains, keeping a keen eye out for trespassers and using magic-infused arrows to defeat monsters and invaders before they can reach elven settlements. Over the centuries, the methods of these elf archers have been learned by members of other races who can also balance arcane aptitude with archery.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Archer&#39;s Lore (Arcane Archer)</name><text>At 3rd level, you learn magical theory or some of the secrets of nature—typical for practitioners of this elven martial tradition. You gain proficiency in either the Arcana or the Nature skill, and you choose to learn either the prestidigitation or druidcraft cantrip.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Shot (Arcane Archer)</name><text>At 3rd level, you learn to unleash special magical effects with some of your shots. When you gain this feature, you learn two Arcane Shot options of your choice (see the “Arcane Shot Options” below). 
	Once per turn when you fire an arrow from a shortbow or longbow as part of the Attack action, you can apply one of your Arcane Shot options to that arrow. You decide to use the option when the arrow hits a creature, unless the option doesn’t involve an attack roll. You have two uses of this ability, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest. 
	You gain an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice when you reach certain levels in this class: 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level. Each option also improves when you become an 18th-level fighter.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Battle Master</name><text>Those who emulate the archetypal Battle Master employ martial techniques passed down through generations. To a Battle Master, combat is an academic field, sometimes including subjects beyond battle such as weaponsmithing and calligraphy. Not every fighter absorbs the lessons of history, theory, and artistry that are reflected in the Battle Master archetype, but those who do are well-rounded fighters of great skill and knowledge.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Student of War (Battle Master)</name><text>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency with one type of artisan’s tools of your choice.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Combat Superiority (Battle Master)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.
	 
Maneuvers: You learn three maneuvers of your choice. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack.
	You learn two additional maneuvers of your choice at 7th, 10th, and 15th level. Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.
	 
Superiority Dice: You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.
	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.
	 
Saving Throws: Some of your maneuvers require your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:
	Maneuver save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice)
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Brute</name><text>Brutes are simple warriors who rely on mighty attacks and their own durability to overcome their enemies. Some brutes combine this physical might with tactical cunning. Others just hit things until those things stop hitting back.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Three Subclasses, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Brute Force (Brute)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you’re able to strike with your weapons with especially brutal force. Whenever you hit with a weapon that you’re proficient with and deal damage, the weapon’s damage increases by an amount based on your level in this class: by 1d4 at 3rd level, 1d6 at 10th level, 1d8 at 16th level, and 1d10 at 20th level.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Three Subclasses, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Cavalier</name><text>The archetypal Cavalier excels at mounted combat. Usually born among the nobility and raised at court, a Cavalier is equally at home leading a cavalry charge or exchanging repartee at a state dinner. Cavaliers also learn how to guard those in their charge from harm, often serving as the protectors of their superiors and of the weak. Drawn to right wrongs or earn prestige, many of these fighters leave their lives of comfort to embark on glorious adventure.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 30</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Cavalier)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, History, Insight, Performance, or Persuasion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 30</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Born to the Saddle (Cavalier)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, your mastery as a rider becomes apparent. You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off your mount and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you’re not incapacitated.
	Finally, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 30</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Unwavering Mark (Cavalier)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can menace your foes, foiling their attacks and punishing them for harming others. When you hit a creature with a  melee weapon attack, you can mark the creature until the end of your next turn. This effect ends early if you are incapacitated or you die, or if someone else marks the creature.
	While it is within 5 feet of you, a creature marked by you has disadvantage on any attack roll that doesn’t target you.
	In addition, if a creature marked by you deals damage to anyone other than you, you can make a special melee weapon attack against the marked creature as a bonus action on your next turn. You have advantage on the attack roll, and if it hits, the attack’s weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to half your fighter level.
	Regardless of the number of creatures you mark, you can make this special attack a number of times equal to your Strength modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 30</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Champion</name><text>The archetypal Champion focuses on the development of raw physical power honed to deadly perfection. Those who model themselves on this archetype combine rigorous training with physical excellence to deal devastating blows.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Critical (Champion)</name><text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Eldritch Knight</name><text>The archetypal Eldritch Knight combines the martial mastery common to all fighters with a careful study of magic. Eldritch Knights use magical techniques similar to those practiced by wizards. They focus their study on two of the eight schools of magic: abjuration and evocation. Abjuration spells grant an Eldritch Knight additional protection in battle, and evocation spells deal damage to many foes at once, extending the fighter’s reach in combat. These knights learn a comparatively small number of spells, committing them to memory instead of keeping them in a spellbook.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 74</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>When you reach 3rd level, you augment your martial prowess with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. 
	 
Cantrips: You learn two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level. 
	 
Spell Slots: The Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. 
	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell shield and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast shield using either slot. 
	 
Spells Known of 1st-level and Higher: You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the abjuration and evocation spells on the wizard spell list.
	The Spells Known column of the Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows when you learn more wizard spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be an abjuration or evocation spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
	The spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic.
	Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an abjuration or evocation spell, unless you’re replacing the spell you gained at 3rd, 8th, 14th, or 20th level from any school of magic. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability: Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. 
	 
Spell save DC = 8+your proficiency bonus+your Intelligence modifier 
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus+your Intelligence modifier
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Weapon Bond (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>At 3rd level, you learn a ritual that creates a magical bond between yourself and one weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual, at the conclusion of which you touch the weapon and forge the bond.
	Once you have bonded a weapon to yourself, you can’t be disarmed of that weapon unless you are incapacitated. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand.
	You can have up to two bonded weapons, but can summon only one at a time with your bonus action. If you attempt to bond with a third weapon, you must break the bond with one of the other two.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Gunslinger</name><text>Most warriors and combat specialists spend their years perfecting the classic arts of swordplay, archery, or polearm tactics. Whether duelist or infantry, martial weapons were seemingly perfected long ago, and the true challenge is to master them.
	However, some minds couldn’t stop with the innovation of the crossbow. Experimentation with alchemical components and rare metals have unlocked the secrets of controlled explosive force. The few who survive these trials of ingenuity may become the first to create, and deftly wield, the first firearms.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Firearm Proficiency (Gunslinger)</name><text>Starting when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with firearms, allowing you to add your proficiency bonus to attacks made with firearms.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Gunsmith (Gunslinger)</name><text>Upon choosing this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with Tinker’s Tools. You may use them to craft ammunition, repair damaged firearms, or even draft and create new ones (DM’s discretion), Some extremely intricate firearms are only available through crafting.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Grit (Gunslinger)</name><text>Also starting at 3rd level, you gain a number of grit points equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). You can spend grit points to perform various "shot" attacks with your firearms. An attack can only be affected by a single shot feature. You can regain spent grit points in the following ways.
	 
	Critical hit with a firearm: Each time you score a critical hit with a firearm attack while in the heat of combat, you regain 1 spent grit point.
	 
	Killing blow with a firearm: Each time you reduce a dangerous creature to 0 hit points with a firearm attack and kill it, you regain 1 spent grit point.
	 
	You also regain all spent grit points after you finish a short or long rest.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Deadeye Shot (Gunslinger)</name><text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can spend 1 grit point to gain advantage on the next attack roll you make with a firearm this round.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Knight</name><text>The Knight is a colossus on the battlefield who can shrug off attacks and protect allies from harm. Knights fight from the saddle when they can, and in combat they are expected to seek out and lock down the mightiest of the enemy’s forces. On adventures, they are the armored bulwark that strives to keep the rest of the party safe.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Born to the Saddle (Knight)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed. In addition, you have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off it, you can automatically land on your feet if you aren’t incapacitated and you fall less than 10 feet.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Implacable Mark (Knight)</name><text>At 3rd level, you excel at foiling attacks and protecting your allies by menacing your foes. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, the target is marked by you until the end of your next turn. A creature ignores this effect if the creature can’t be frightened. 
	The marked target has disadvantage on any attack roll against a creature other than you or someone else who marked it. 
	If a target marked by you is within 5 feet of you on its turn and it moves at least 1 foot or makes an attack that suffers disadvantage from this feature, you can make one melee weapon attack against it using your reaction. This attack roll has advantage, and if it hits, the attack’s weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to your fighter level. 
	You can make this special attack even if you have already expended your reaction this round, but not if you have already used your reaction this turn. You can make this attack three times, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Monster Hunter</name><text>As an archetypal Monster Hunter, you are an expert at defeating supernatural threats. Typically mentored by an older, experienced Monster Hunter, you learn to overcome a variety of unnatural defenses and attacks, including those of undead, lycanthropes, and other creatures of horror.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Monster Hunter)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Nature, or Perception. You can gain proficiency with a tool of your choice in place of one skill choice.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Combat Superiority (Monster Hunter)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice. 
	 
Superiority Dice:
	You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.
	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level. 
	 
Using Superiority Dice:
	You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits: 
	 
• When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied. 
	 
• When you damage a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the damage roll. You can use this ability after rolling damage. If the attack causes the target to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, it has disadvantage on that save. 
	 
• When you make an Intelligence, a Wisdom, or a Charisma saving throw, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this feature only before you learn if the save succeeded or failed. 
	 
• When you make a Wisdom (Perception) check to detect a hidden creature or object, or a Wisdom (Insight) check to determine if someone is lying to you, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this feature after seeing the total but before learning if you succeeded or failed.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Hunter&#39;s Mysticism (Monster Hunter</name><text>At 3rd level, your study of the supernatural gives you a limited ability to use magic. You can cast detect magic as a ritual. You can cast protection from evil and good, but you cannot cast it again with this feature until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
	In addition, you gain the ability to speak one of the following languages of your choice: Abyssal, Celestial, or Infernal.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Psi Warrior</name><text>Awake to the psionic power within, a Psi Warrior is a fighter who augments their physical might with psi-infused weapon strikes, telekinetic lashes, and barriers of mental force. Many githyanki train to become such warriors, as do some of the most disciplined high elves. In the world of Eberron, many young kalashtar dream of becoming Psi Warriors.

As a Psi Warrior, you might have honed your psionic abilities through solo discipline, unlocked it under the tutelage of a master, or refined it at an academy dedicated to wielding the mind’s power as both weapon and shield.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Psionic Power (Psi Warrior)</name><text>You harbor a wellspring of psionic energy within yourself. This energy is represented by your Psionic Energy dice, which are each a d6. You have a number of these dice equal to twice your proficiency bonus, and they fuel various psionic powers you have, which are detailed below.

Some of your powers expend the Psionic Energy die they use, as specified in a power’s description, and you can’t use a power if it requires you to use a die when your dice are all expended. You regain all your expended Psionic Energy dice when you finish a long rest. In addition, as a bonus action, you can regain one expended Psionic Energy die, but you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.

When you reach certain levels in this class, the size of your Psionic Energy dice increases: at 5th level (d8), 11th level (d10), and 17th level (d12).

The powers below use your Psionic Energy dice.

Protective Field. When you or another creature you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to expend one Psionic Energy die, roll the die, and reduce the damage taken by the number rolled plus your Intelligence modifier (minimum reduction of 1), as you create a momentary shield of telekinetic force.

Psionic Strike. You can propel your weapons with psionic force. Once on each of your turns, immediately after you hit a target within 30 feet of you with an attack and deal damage to it with a weapon, you can expend one Psionic Energy die, rolling it and dealing force damage to the target equal to the number rolled plus your Intelligence modifier.

Telekinetic Movement. You can move an object or a creature with your mind. As an action, you target one loose object that is Large or smaller or one willing creature, other than yourself. If you can see the target and it is within 30 feet of you, you can move it up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Alternatively, if it is a Tiny object, you can move it to or from your hand. Either way, you can move the target horizontally, vertically, or both. Once you take this action, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, unless you expend a Psionic Energy die to take it again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Purple Dragon Knight</name><text>Purple Dragon Knights are warriors who hail from the kingdom of Cormyr. Pledged to protect the crown, they take the fight against evil beyond the kingdom’s borders. They are tasked with wandering the land as knights errant, relying on their judgment, bravery, and fidelity to guide them in defeating evildoers.
	A Purple Dragon Knight inspires greatness in others by committing brave deeds in battle. The mere presence of a knight in a hamlet is enough to cause some orcs and bandits to seek easier prey. A lone knight is a skilled warrior, but a knight leading a band of allies can transform even the most poorly equipped militia into a ferocious war band.
	A knight prefers to lead through deeds, not words. As a knight spearheads an attack, the knight’s actions can awaken reserves of courage and conviction in allies that they never suspected they had.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 128</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Restriction: Knighthood (Purple Dragon Knight)</name><text>Purple Dragon Knights are tied to a specific order of Cormyrean knighthood.
	Banneret serves as the generic name for this archetype if you use it in other campaign settings or to model warlords other than the Purple Dragon Knights.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 128</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Rallying Cry (Purple Dragon Knight)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn how to inspire your allies to fight on past their injuries.
	When you use your Second Wind feature, you can choose up to three creatures within 60 feet of you that are allied with you. Each one regains hit points equal to your fighter level, provided that the creature can see or hear you.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 128</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Samurai</name><text>The Samurai is a fighter who draws on an implacable fighting spirit to overcome enemies. A Samurai’s resolve is nearly unbreakable, and the enemies in a Samurai’s path have two choices: yield or die fighting.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Samurai)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: History, Insight, Performance, or Persuasion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Spirit (Samurai)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, your intensity in battle can shield you and help you strike true. As a bonus action on your turn, you can give yourself advantage on weapon attack rolls until the end of your current turn. When you do so, you also gain 5 temporary hit points. The number of temporary hit points increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 10 at 10th level and 15 at 15th level.
	You can use this feature three times, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Scout</name><text>The archetypal Scout excels at finding safe passage through dangerous regions. Scouts usually favor light armor and ranged weapons, but they are comfortable using heavier gear when faced with intense fighting.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Scout)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in three of the following skills of your choice: Acrobatics, Athletics, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You can choose to gain proficiency with thieves’ tools in place of one skill choice.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Combat Superiority (Scout)</name><text>At 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.
	 
Superiority Dice:
	You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a long or short rest. You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.
	 
Using Superiority Dice:
	You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits.
	 
• When you make a check that allows you to apply your proficiency in Athletics, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival, you can expend one superiority die to bolster the check. Add half the number rolled on the superiority die (rounding up) to your check. You apply this bonus after making the check but before learning if it was successful.
	 
• When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.
	 
• If you are hit by an attack while wearing light or medium armor, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction, adding the number rolled to your AC. If the attack still hits, you take half damage from it.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Natural Explorer (Scout)</name><text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you’re proficient in.
	While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits.
	 
• Difficult terrain doesn’t slow your group’s travel.
	 
• Your group can’t become lost except by magical means.
	 
• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.
	 
• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
	 
• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.
	 
• While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.
	 
	You choose additional favored terrain types at 7th and 15th level.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Sharpshooter</name><text>The Sharpshooter is a master of ranged combat. An excellent sniper and eagle-eyed scout, this fighter is a perilous foe who can defeat an entire war band so long as they are kept at range.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Steady Aim (Sharpshooter)</name><text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your aim becomes deadly. As a bonus action on your turn, you can take careful aim at a creature you can see that is within range of a ranged weapon you’re wielding. Until the end of this turn, your ranged attacks with that weapon gain two benefits against the target: 
	 
• The attacks ignore half and three-quarters cover. 
	 
• On each hit, the weapon deals additional damage to the target equal to 2 + half your fighter level. 
	You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archtype: Rune Knight</name><text>Rune Knights enhance their martial prowess using the supernatural power of runes, an ancient practice that originated with giants. Rune cutters can be found among any family of giants, and you likely learned your methods first or second hand from such a mystical artisan. Whether you found the giant’s work carved into a hill or cave, learned of the runes from a sage, or met the giant in person, you studied the giant’s craft and learned how to apply magic runes to empower your equipment.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Rune Knight)</name><text>You gain proficiency with smith’s tools, and you learn to speak, read, and write Giant.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Giant Might (Rune Knight)</name><text>You have learned how to imbue yourself with the might of giants. As a bonus action, you magically gain the following benefits, which last for 1 minute:

If you are smaller than Large, you become Large, along with anything you are wearing. If you lack the room to become Large, your size doesn’t change.

You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.

Once on each of your turns, one of your attacks with a weapon or an unarmed strike can deal an extra 1d6 damage to a target on a hit.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Rune Carver (Rune Knight)</name><text>You can use magic runes to enhance your gear. You learn two runes of your choice, from among the runes described below, and each time you gain a level in this class, you can replace one rune you know with a different one from this feature. When you reach certain levels in this class, you learn additional runes, as shown in the Runes Known table.

Runes Known
Fighter Level	Number of Runes
3rd	                       2
7th	                       3
10th	                4
15th	                5
Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch a number of objects equal to the number of runes you know, and you inscribe a different rune onto each of the objects. To be eligible, an object must be a weapon, a suit of armor, a shield, a piece of jewelry, or something else you can wear or hold in a hand. Your rune remains on an object until you finish a long rest, and an object can bear only one of your runes at a time.

The following runes are available to you when you learn a rune. If a rune has a level requirement, you must be at least that level in this class to learn the rune. If a rune requires a saving throw, your Rune Magic save DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Martial Archetype: Echo Knight</name><text>A mysterious and feared frontline warrior of the Kryn Dynasty, the Echo Knight has mastered the art of using dunamis to summon the fading shades of unrealized timelines to aid them in battle. Surrounded by echoes of their own might, they charge into the fray as a cycling swarm of shadows and strikes.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Manifest Echo (Echo Knight)</name><text>You can use a bonus action to magically manifest an echo of yourself in an unoccupied space you can see within 15 feet of you. This echo is a magical, translucent, gray image of you that lasts until it is destroyed, until you dismiss it as a bonus action, until you manifest another echo, or until you’re incapacitated.

Your echo has AC 14 + your proficiency bonus, 1 hit point, and immunity to all conditions. If it has to make a saving throw, it uses your saving throw bonus for the roll. It is the same size as you, and it occupies its space. On your turn, you can mentally command the echo to move up to 30 feet in any direction (no action required). If your echo is ever more than 30 feet from you at the end of your turn, it is destroyed.

You can use the echo in the following ways:

As a bonus action, you can teleport, magically swapping places with your echo at a cost of 15 feet of your movement, regardless of the distance between the two of you.
When you take the Attack action on your turn, any attack you make with that action can originate from your space or the echo’s space. You make this choice for each attack.
When a creature that you can see within 5 feet of your echo moves at least 5 feet away from it, you can use your reaction to make an opportunity attack against that creature as if you were in the echo’s space.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Unleash Incarnation (Echo Knight)</name><text>You can heighten your echo’s fury. Whenever you take the Attack action, you can make one additional melee attack from the echo’s position.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>4</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat><feat><name>Martial Versatility: Optional Feature</name><text>Whenever you reach a level in this class that grants the Ability Score Improvement feature, you can do one of the following, as you shift the focus of your martial practice:

Replace a fighting style you know with another fighting style available to fighters.
If you know any maneuvers from the Battle Master archetype, you can replace one maneuver you know with a different maneuver.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>5</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Extra Attack</name><text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.
	The number of attacks increases to three when you reach 11th level in this class and to four when you reach 20th level in this class.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>6</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>7</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Shot Option (3rd)</name><text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Magic Arrow (Arcane Archer)</name><text>At 7th level, you gain the ability to infuse arrows with magic. Whenever you fire a nonmagical arrow from a shortbow or longbow, you can make it maguical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical attacs and damage. The magic fades from the arrow immediately after it hits or misses its target.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Curving Shot (Arcane Archer)</name><text>At 7th level, you learn how to direct an errant arrow toward a new target. When you make an attack roll with a magic arrow and miss, you can use a bonus action to reroll the attack roll against a different target within 60 feet of the original target.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Shot Option (3rd)</name><text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Know Your Enemy (Battle Master)</name><text>Starting at 7th level, if you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities compared to your own. The DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regard to two of the following characteristics of your choice.
	 
• Strength score
• Dexterity score
• Constitution score
• Armor Class
• Current hit points
	 
• Total class levels (if any)
	 
• Fighter class levels (if any)
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Additional Maneuvers (Battle Master)</name><text>You learn two additional Combat Superiority maneuvers.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 74</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Brutish Durability (Brute)</name><text>Beginning at 7th level, your toughness allows you to shrug off assaults that would devastate others.
	Whenever you make a saving throw, roll 1d6 and add the die to your saving throw total. If applying this bonus to a death saving throw increases the total to 20 or higher, you gain the benefits of rolling a 20 on the d20.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Three Subclasses, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Warding Maneuver (Cavalier)</name><text>At 7th level, you learn to fend off strikes directed at you, your mount, ot other creatures nearby. If you or a creature you can see within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can roll 1d8 as a reaction if you’re wielding a melee weapon or a shield. Roll the de, and add the number rolled to the target’s AC against that attack. If the attack still hits, the target has resistance against the attack’s damage.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 30</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Remarkable Athlete (Champion)</name><text>Starting at 7th level, you can add half your proficiency bonus (round up) to any Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution check you make that doesn’t already use your proficiency bonus.
	In addition, when you make a running long jump, the distance you can cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Strength modifier.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>War Magic (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Quickdraw (Gunslinger)</name><text>When you reach 7th level, you gain a +2 bonus to initiative. You can also stow a firearm, then draw another firearm as a single object interaction on your turn.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional><mod><type>12</type><value>2</value></mod></feat><feat><name>Violent Shot (Gunslinger)</name><text>Starting at 7th level, you’ve discovered ways to push your firearms past their intended potential at the peril of damaging them. You can spend 1 or more grit points before making an attack roll with a firearm. For each grit point spent, that attack gains +2 to the firearm’s misfire score.
	If the attack hits, you can roll one additional weapon damage die per grit point spent when determining damage of the attack.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Noble Cavalry (Knight)</name><text>At 7th level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, History, Insight, Persuasion, or Religion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Monster Slayer (Monster Hunter)</name><text>At 7th level, whenever you expend superiority dice to add to a damage roll, you can expend up to two dice instead of just one, adding both to the roll. Both dice are expended as normal. If the target of your attack is an aberration, a fey, a fiend, or an undead, you deal maximum damage with both dice, instead of rolling them.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Telekinetic Adept (Psi Warrior)</name><text>You have mastered new ways to use your telekinetic abilities, detailed below.

Psi-Powered Leap. As a bonus action, you can propel your body with your mind. You gain a flying speed equal to twice your walking speed until the end of the current turn. Once you take this bonus action, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, unless you expend a Psionic Energy die to take it again.

Telekinetic Thrust. When you deal damage to a target with your Psionic Strike, you can force the target to make a Strength saving throw against a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. If the save fails, you can knock the target prone or move it up to 10 feet in any direction horizontally.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Royal Envoy (Purple Dragon Knight)</name><text>A Purple Dragon Knight serves as an envoy of the Cormyrean crown. Knights of high standing are expected to conduct themselves with grace.
	At 7th level, you gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in it, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Insight, Intimidation, or Performance.
	Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses Persuasion. You receive this benefit regardless of the skill proficiency you gain from this feature.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 128</text><optional>1</optional><proficiency>113</proficiency><mod></mod></feat><feat><name>Elegant Courtier (Samurai)</name><text>Starting at 7th level, your discipline and attention to detail allow you to excel in social situation. Whenever you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check, you gain a bonus to the check equal to your Wisdom modifier.
	Your self-control also causes you to gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws. If you already have this proficiency, you instead gain proficiency in Intelligence or Charisma saving throws (your choice).
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional><proficiency>4</proficiency></feat><feat><name>Careful Eyes (Sharpshooter)</name><text>Starting at 7th level, you excel at picking out
hidden enemies and other threats. You can take
the Search action as a bonus action.

	You also gain proficiency in the Perception,
Investigation, or Survival skill (choose one).
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Runic Shield (Rune Knight)</name><text>You learn to invoke your rune magic to protect your allies. When another creature you can see within 60 feet of you is hit by an attack roll, you can use your reaction to force the attacker to reroll the d20 and use the new roll.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Echo Avatar (Echo Knight)</name><text>You can temporarily transfer your consciousness to your echo. As an action, you can see through your echo’s eyes and hear through its ears. During this time, you are deafened and blinded. You can sustain this effect for up to 10 minutes, and you can end it at any time (requires no action). While your echo is being used in this way, it can be up to 1,000 feet away from you without being destroyed.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>8</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>9</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>2,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Indomitable</name><text>Beginning at 9th level, you can reroll a saving throw that you fail. If you do so, you must use the new roll, and you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest. You can use this feature twice between long rests starting at 13th level and three times between long rests starting at 17th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>10</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Shot Option (4th)</name><text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Combat Superiority (Battle Master)</name><text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 74</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Additional Maneuvers (Battle Master)</name><text>You learn two additional Combat Superiority maneuvers.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Additional Fighting Style (Brute)</name><text>At 10th level, you can choose a second option from the Fighting Style feature.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Three Subclasses, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Archery</name><text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>0</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Ambush</name><text>When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or an initiative roll, you can expend one superiority die and add the die to the roll, provided you aren’t incapacitated.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Bait And Switch</name><text>When you’re within 5 feet of a creature on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and switch places with that creature, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement and the creature is willing and isn’t incapacitated. This movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.

Roll the superiority die. Until the start of your next turn, you or the other creature (your choice) gains a bonus to AC equal to the number rolled.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Brace</name><text>When a creature you can see moves into the reach you have with the melee weapon you’re wielding, you can use your reaction to expend one superiority die and make one attack against the creature, using that weapon. If the attack hits, add the superiority die to the weapon’s damage roll.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Commanding Presence</name><text>When you make a Charisma (Intimidation), a Charisma (Performance), or a Charisma (Persuasion) check, you can expend one superiority die and add the superiority die to the ability check.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter</name><text>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Defense</name><text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>1</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name><text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>2</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Grappling Strike</name><text>Immediately after you hit a creature with a melee attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and then try to grapple the target as a bonus action (see the Player’s Handbook for rules on grappling). Add the superiority die to your Strength (Athletics) check.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name><text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name><text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Protection</name><text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Quick Toss</name><text>As a bonus action, you can expend one superiority die and make a ranged attack with a weapon that has the thrown property. You can draw the weapon as part of making this attack. If you hit, add the superiority die to the weapon’s damage roll.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Tactical Assessment</name><text>When you make an Intelligence (Investigation), an Intelligence (History), or a Wisdom (Insight) check, you can expend one superiority die and add the superiority die to the ability check.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter</name><text>You excel at defending narrow passages, doorways, and other tight spaces. As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name><text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Hold the Line (Cavalier)</name><text>At 10th level, you become a master of locking down your enemies. Creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you when they move 5 feet or more while within your reach, and if you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, the target’s speed is reduced to 0 until the end of the current turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 30</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Additional Fighting Style (Champion)</name><text>At 10th level, you can choose a second option from the Fighting Style class feature.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Archery</name><text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>0</special></feat><feat><name>Flighting Style: Ambush</name><text>When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or an initiative roll, you can expend one superiority die and add the die to the roll, provided you aren’t incapacitated.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Brace</name><text>When a creature you can see moves into the reach you have with the melee weapon you’re wielding, you can use your reaction to expend one superiority die and make one attack against the creature, using that weapon. If the attack hits, add the superiority die to the weapon’s damage roll.</text></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Bait And Switch</name><text>When you’re within 5 feet of a creature on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and switch places with that creature, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement and the creature is willing and isn’t incapacitated. This movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.

Roll the superiority die. Until the start of your next turn, you or the other creature (your choice) gains a bonus to AC equal to the number rolled.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Commanding Presence</name><text>When you make a Charisma (Intimidation), a Charisma (Performance), or a Charisma (Persuasion) check, you can expend one superiority die and add the superiority die to the ability check.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter</name><text>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional><mod><type>5</type><value>1</value></mod></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Defense</name><text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>1</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Grappling Strike</name><text>Immediately after you hit a creature with a melee attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and then try to grapple the target as a bonus action (see the Player’s Handbook for rules on grappling). Add the superiority die to your Strength (Athletics) check.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name><text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional><special>2</special></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name><text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name><text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Quick Toss</name><text>As a bonus action, you can expend one superiority die and make a ranged attack with a weapon that has the thrown property. You can draw the weapon as part of making this attack. If you hit, add the superiority die to the weapon’s damage roll.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Tactical Assessment</name><text>When you make an Intelligence (Investigation), an Intelligence (History), or a Wisdom (Insight) check, you can expend one superiority die and add the superiority die to the ability check.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Protection</name><text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter</name><text>You excel at defending narrow passages, doorways, and other tight spaces. As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, p. 1</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name><text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Eldritch Strike (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>At 10th level, you learn how to make your weapon strikes undercut a creature’s resistance to your spells. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, that creature has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes against a spell you cast before the end of your next turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Trick Shot (Gunslinger)</name><text>By 10th level, you’ve honed your aim to fire off targeted shots to disable an opponent. You can spend 1 grit point before making an attack roll to target a specific location on the target’s body. If the specified body part cannot be seen, or the target lacks the part in question, only normal damage is suffered with no additional effect.
	 
Trick Shot DC=8+your proficiency bonus+your desxterity modifier
	 
	Head: On a hit, the target takes normal damage and must make a Constitution saving throw or suffer disadvantage on attacks until the end of their next turn.
	 
	Arms: On a hit, the target takes normal damage and must make a Strength saving throw or drop 1 held item of your choice.
	 
	Torso: On a hit, the target takes normal damage and is pushed up to 10 feet directly away from you.
	 
	Legs/Wings: On a hit, the target takes normal damage and must make a Strength saving throw or get knocked prone.
	 
Prone:
• A prone creature&#39;s only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.
	
• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.
	
• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Hold the Line (Knight)</name><text>At 10th level, you master the ability to harass and slow your enemies. As a reaction when a creature moves at least 1 foot within 5 feet of you, you can make one melee weapon attack against that creature. If you hit, the attack’s weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to half your fighter level, and the target’s speed is reduced to 0 until the end of this turn.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Combat Superiority (Monster Hunter)</name><text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Guarded Mind (Psi Warrior)</name><text>The psionic energy flowing through you has bolstered your mind. You have resistance to psychic damage. Moreover, if you start your turn charmed or frightened, you can expend a Psionic Energy die and end every effect on yourself subjecting you to those conditions.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Inspiring Surge (Purple Dragon Knight)</name><text>Starting at 10th level, when you use your Action Surge feature, you can choose one creature within 60 feet of you that is allied with you. That creature can make one melee or ranged weapon attack with its reaction, provided that it can see or hear you.
	Starting at 18th level, you can choose two allies within 60 feet of you, rather than one.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 128</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Tireless Spirit (Samurai)</name><text>Starting at 10th level, when you roll initiative and have no uses of Fighting Spirit remaining, you regain one use.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Combat Superiority (Scout)</name><text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Close-Quarters Shooting (Sharpshooter)</name><text>At 10th level, you learn to handle yourself in close combat. Making a ranged attack roll while within 5 feet of an enemy doesn’t impose disadvantage on your roll. 
	In addition, if you hit a creature within 5 feet of you with a ranged attack on your turn, that creature can’t take reactions until the end of this turn.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Great Stature (Rune Knight)</name><text>The magic of your runes permanently alters you. When you gain this feature, roll 3d4. You grow a number of inches in height equal to the roll.

Moreover, the extra damage you deal with your Giant’s Might feature increases to 1d8.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Shadow Martyr (Echo Knight)</name><text>You can make your echo throw itself in front of an attack directed at another creature that you can see. Before the attack roll is made, you can use your reaction to teleport the echo to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the targeted creature. The attack roll that triggered the reaction is instead made against your echo.

Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>11</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>12</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>13</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>14</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>15</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Shot Option (5th)</name><text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Ever-Ready Shot (Arcane Archer)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, your magical archery is available whenever battle starts. If you roll initiative and have no uses of Arcane Shot remaining, you regain one use of it.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Relentless (Battle Master)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 74</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Additional Maneuvers (Battle Master)</name><text>You learn two additional Combat Superiority maneuvers.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Devastating Critical (Brute)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, when you score a critical hit with a weapon attack, you gain a bonus to that weapon’s damage roll equal to your level in this class.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Three Subclasses, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Ferocious Charger (Cavalier)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, you can run down your foes, whether you’re mounted or not. If you move at least 10 feet in a straight line right before attacking a creature and you hit it with the attack, that target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC * + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or be knocked prone. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.
	 
Prone:
• A prone creature&#39;s only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.
	
• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.
	
• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Superior Critical (Champion)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 18-20.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Charge (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>At 15th level, you gain the ability to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see when you use your Action Surge. You can teleport before or after the additional action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Lightning Reload (Gunslinger)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, you can reload any firearm as a bonus action.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Piercing Shot (Gunslinger)</name><text>By 15th level, you’ve refined your deadly gunplay to allow certain shots to pierce through foes and continue on to damage others. You can spend 1 grit point before making an attack roll with a firearm that deals piercing damage. If the attack hits, you make an attack roll against every creature directly behind the target within your first range increment. Only the initial attack can misfire.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Rapid Strike (Knight)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Relentless (Monster Hunter)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain one superiority die.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bulwark Of Force (Psi Warrior)</name><text>You can shield yourself and others with telekinetic force. As a bonus action, you can choose creatures, which can include you, that you can see within 30 feet of you, up to a number of creatures equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one creature). Each of the chosen creatures is protected by half cover for 1 minute or until you’re incapacitated.

Once you take this bonus action, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest, unless you expend a Psionic Energy die to take it again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bulwark (Purple Dragon Knight)</name><text>Beginning at 15th level, you can extend the benefit of your Indomitable feature to an ally. When you decide to use Indomitable to reroll an Intelligence, a Wisdom, or a Charisma saving throw and you aren’t incapacitated, you can choose one ally within 60 feet of you that also failed its saving throw against the same effect. If that creature can see or hear you, it can reroll its saving throw and must use the new roll.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 128</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Rapid Strike (Samurai)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you take the Attack action on your turn and have advantage on the attack roll against one of the targets, you can forgo the advantage for that roll to make an additional weapon attack against that target, as part of the same action. You can do so no more than once per turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Relentless (Scout)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Rapid Strike (Sharpshooter)</name><text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master Of Runes (Rune Knight)</name><text>You can invoke each rune you know from your Rune Carver feature twice, rather than once, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Reclaim Potential (Echo Knight)</name><text>You’ve learned to absorb the fleeting magic of your echo. When an echo of yours is destroyed by taking damage, you can gain a number of temporary hit points equal to 2d6 + your Constitution modifier, provided you don’t already have temporary hit points.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>16</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (7th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>17</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>18</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Shot Option (6th)</name><text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 28</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Survivor (Brute)</name><text>At 18th level, you attain the pinnacle of resilience in battle. At the start of each of your turns in combat, you regain hit points equal to 5 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point). You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points or if you have more than half of your hit points left.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Three Subclasses, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Vigilant Defender (Cavalier)</name><text>Starting at 18th level, you respond to danger with extraordinary vigilance. In combat, you get a special reaction that you can take once on every creature’s turn, except your turn. You can use this special reaction only to make opportunity attacks, and you can’t use it on the same turn that you take your normal reaction.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Survivor (Champion)</name><text>At 18th level, you attain the pinnacle of resilience in battle. At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to 5 + your Constitution modifier if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 73</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved War Magic (Eldritch Knight)</name><text>Starting at 18th level, when you use your action to cast a spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 75</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Vicious Intent (Gunslinger)</name><text>At 18th level, your firearm attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Hemorrhaging Critical (Gunslinger)</name><text>Upon reaching 18th level, whenever you score a critical hit on an attack with a firearm, the target additionally suffers half of the damage from the attack at the end of its next turn.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Gunslinger Martial Archetype for Fighters, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Defender&#39;s Blade (Knight)</name><text>At 18th level, you respond to danger with extraordinary vigilance. You can use your reaction for an opportunity attack even if you have already expended your reaction this round, but not if you have already used your reaction this turn. 
	In addition, you gain a +1 bonus to AC while wearing heavy armor.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Telekinetic Master (Psi Warrior)</name><text>Your ability to move creatures and objects with your mind is matched by few. You can cast the telekinesis spell, requiring no components, and your spellcasting ability for the spell is Intelligence. On each of your turns while you concentrate on the spell, including the turn when you cast it, you can make one attack with a weapon as a bonus action.

Once you cast the spell with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest, unless you expend a Psionic Energy die to cast it again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Strength Before Death (Samurai)</name><text>Starting at 18th level, your fighting spirit can delay the grasp of death. If you take damage that reduces you to 0 hit points and doesn’t kill you outright, you can use your reaction to delay falling unconscious, and you can immediately take an extra turn, interrupting the current turn. While you have 0 hit points during that extra turn, taking damage causes death saving throw failures as normal, and three deaths aving throw failures can still kill you. Wshen the extra turn ends, you fall unconscious if you still have 0 hit points.
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 31</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Snap Shot (Sharpshooter)</name><text>Starting at 18th level, you are ever ready to spring into action. If you take the Attack action on your first turn of a combat, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as part of that action.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 4</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Runic Juggernaut (Rune Knight)</name><text>You learn how to amplify your rune-powered transformation. As a result, the extra damage you deal with the Giant’s Might feature increases to 1d10. Moreover, when you use that feature, your size can increase to Huge, and while you are that size, your reach increases by 5 feet.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Legion Of One (Echo Knight)</name><text>You can use a bonus action to create two echoes with your Manifest Echo feature, and these echoes can coexist. If you try to create a third echo, the previous two echoes are destroyed. Anything you can do from one echo’s position can be done from the other’s instead.

In addition, when you roll initiative and have no uses of your Unleash Incarnation feature left, you regain one use of that feature.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>19</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (8th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 6th, 8th, 12th, 14th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 72</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>20</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><spellAbility>3</spellAbility><spell><name>Absorb Elements</name><school>1</school><level>1</level><time>1 reaction, which you take when you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage</time><range>Self</range><s>1</s><duration>1 round</duration><text>The spell captures some of the incoming energy, lessening its effect on you and storing it for your next melee attack. You have resistance to the triggering damage type until the start of your next turn. Also, the first time you hit with a melee attack on your next turn, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage of the triggering type, and the spell ends.
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 150^Elemental Evil Player&#39;s Companion, p. 15^Princes of the Apocalypse, p. 233</text><roll>1d6</roll><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Ranger</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Comprehend Languages</name><school>3</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a pinch of soot and salt</materials><duration>1 hour</duration><text>For the duration, you understand the literal meaning of any spoken language that you hear. You also understand any spoken language that you hear. You also understand any written language that you see, but you must be touching the surface on which the words are written. It takes about 1 minute to read one page of text. 
	This spell doesn&#39;t decode secret messages in a text or glyph, such as an arcane sigil, that isn&#39;t part of a written language. 

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 224</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Prestidigitation</name><school>8</school><time>1 action</time><range>10 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Up to 1 hour</duration><text>This spell is a minor magical trick that novice spellcasters use for practice. You create one of the following magical effects within range: 
	• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor. 
	• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor. 
	• You instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire. 
	• You instantaneously clean or soil an object no larger than 1 cubic foot. 
	• You chill, warm, or flavor up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving material for 1 hour. 
	• You make a color, a small mark, or a symbol appear on an object or a surface for 1 hour. 
	• You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image that can fit in your hand and that lasts until the end of your next turn. 
	If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 267</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Soul Binder</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Shield</name><school>1</school><level>1</level><time>1 reaction</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>1 round</duration><text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 275</text><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock (Hexblade)</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (Witchcraft)</sclass><sclass>Witch</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Shocking Grasp</name><school>5</school><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>Lightning springs from your hand to deliver a shock to a creature you try to touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. You have advantage on the attack roll if the target is wearing armor made of metal. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 lightning damage, and it can&#39;t take reactions until the start of its next turn. 
	The spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 275</text><roll>1d8</roll><sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass><sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass></spell></class><class><name>Cleric</name><level>2</level><hdCurrent>2</hdCurrent><hd>2</hd><wealth>5d4x10</wealth><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><proficiency>4</proficiency><proficiency>5</proficiency><numClassSkills>2</numClassSkills><armor>light armor, medium armor, shields</armor><weapons>simple weapons</weapons><tools>none</tools><feat><name>Multiclass Cleric</name><text>To multiclass as a Cleric, you must meet the following prerequisites:
• Wisdom 13
 
You gain the following proficiencies:
• light armor, medium armor, shields
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 163</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the cleric spell list.
	 
Cantrips:
	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn an additional cleric cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. 
	 
Preparing and Casting Spells:
	The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability:
	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier 
	 
Ritual Casting:
	You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. 
	 
Spellcasting Focus:
	You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 58</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain</name><text>Choose one domain related to your deity: Knowledge, Life, Light, Nature, Tempest, Trickery, or War. Each domain is detailed at the end of the class description, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels. 
	 
Domain Spells:
	Each domain has a list of spells — its domain spells — that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.
	If you have a domain spell that doesn’t appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 58</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Tempest Domain</name><text>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain — including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor — govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath. 
	 
Tempest Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — fog cloud, thunderwave
3rd — gust of wind, shatter
5th — call lightning, sleet storm
7th — control water, ice storm
9th — destructive wave, insect plague
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Tempest Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Wrath of the Storm (Tempest Domain)</name><text>Also at 1st level, you can thunderously rebuke attackers. When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage (your choice) on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity</name><text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.
	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.
	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.
	Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses. 
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 58</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name><text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Destructive Wrath (Tempest Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to wield the power of the storm with unchecked ferocity.
	When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional><expanded>0</expanded></feat><tracker><label>Channel Divinity</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><value>1</value><formula>1</formula></tracker><autolevel><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Starting Cleric</name><text>As a 1st-level Cleric, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields
• Weapons: simple weapons
• Tools: none
• Skills: Choose two from History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion
 
You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) a mace or (b) a warhammer (if proficient)
• (a) scale mail, (b) leather armor, or (c) chain mail (if proficient)
• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon
• (a) a priest&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack
• A shield and a holy symbol
 
Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.
 
Source: </text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Multiclass Cleric</name><text>To multiclass as a Cleric, you must meet the following prerequisites:
• Wisdom 13
 
You gain the following proficiencies:
• light armor, medium armor, shields
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 163</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the cleric spell list.
	 
Cantrips:
	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn an additional cleric cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. 
	 
Preparing and Casting Spells:
	The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability:
	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier 
	 
Ritual Casting:
	You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. 
	 
Spellcasting Focus:
	You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 58</text></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain</name><text>Choose one domain related to your deity: Knowledge, Life, Light, Nature, Tempest, Trickery, or War. Each domain is detailed at the end of the class description, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels. 
	 
Domain Spells:
	Each domain has a list of spells — its domain spells — that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.
	If you have a domain spell that doesn’t appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 58</text></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Arcana Domain</name><text>Magic is an energy that suffuses the multiverse and that fuels both destruction and creation. Gods of the Arcana domain know the secrets and potential of magic intimately. For some of these gods, magical knowledge is a great responsibility that comes with a special understanding of the nature of reality. Other gods of Arcana see magic as pure power, to be used as its wielder sees fit.
	The gods of this domain are often associated with knowledge, as learning and arcane power tend to go hand-in-hand. In the Realms, deities of this domain include Azuth and Mystra, as well as Corellon Larethian of the elven pantheon. In other worlds, this domain includes Hecate, Math Mathonwy, and Isis; the triple moon gods of Solinari, Lunitari, and Nuitari of Krynn; and Boccob, Vecna, and Wee Jas of Greyhawk.
	 
Arcana Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared
	 
1st — detect magic, magic missile
3rd — magic weapon, Nystul’s magic aura
5th — dispel magic, magic circle
7th — arcane eye, Leomund’s secret chest
9th — planar binding, teleportation circle
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 125</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Arcane Initiate (Arcana Domain)</name><text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency in the Arcana skill, and you gain two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. For you, these cantrips count as cleric cantrips.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 125</text><optional>1</optional><proficiency>102</proficiency></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Blood Domain</name><text>Originally developed in Wildemount by the Claret Orders, the Blood domain centers around the understanding of the natural life force within one’s own physical body. The power of blood is the power of sacrifice, the balance of life and death, and the spirit’s anchor within the mortal shell.
	The Gods of Blood seek to tap into the connection between body and soul through divine means, exploit the hidden reserves of will within one’s own vitality, and even manipulate or corrupt the body of others through these secret rites of crimson. Almost any neutral or evil deity can claim some influence over the secrets of blood magic and this domain, while the gods who watch from more moral realms shun its use beyond extenuating circumstance.
	When casting divine spells as a Blood Domain cleric, consider ways to occasionally flavor your descriptions to tailor the magic’s effect on the opponent’s blood and vitality. Hold person might involve locking a target’s body into place from the blood stream out, preventing them from moving. Cure wounds may feature the controlling of blood like a needle and thread to close lacerations. Guardian of faith could be a floating, crimson spirit of dripping viscera who watches the vicinity with burning red eyes. Have fun with the themes!
	 
Blood Domain Spells:
1st — sleep, ray of sickness
3rd — ray of enfeeblement, crown of madness
5th — haste, slow
7th — blight, stoneskin
9th — dominate person, hold monster.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 101</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Blood Domain)</name><text>At 1st Level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 101</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bloodletting Focus (Blood Domain)</name><text>From 1st level, your divine magics draw the blood from inflicted wounds, worsening the agony of your nearby foes. When you use a spell of 1st level or higher to damage to any creatures that have blood, those creatures suffer additional necrotic damage equal to 2 + the spell’s level.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 101</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Craft Domain</name><text>From the earliest days, gods of the craft domain have inspired their worshipers to cultivate and develop useful arts and technologies, moving artisans and craftspeople to create and innovate.  As such, these gods are some of the most nurturing and sustaining patrons, propelling their faithful to new heights of culture and civilization through the crafts they inspire.
	Many of the gods of the craft domain also have knowledge within their portfolio, for knowledge and curiosity are the spark that ignites the pursuit of craft.  In the Realms, Gond is the quintessential deity of the craft domain, while Flandal Steelskin of the gnomish pantheon and Laduguer of the duergar pantheon fulfill similar functions.  In other worlds, craft domain gods include Hephaestus of the Greek pantheon, Imhotep and Ptah of the Egyptian pantheon, Lugh of the Celtic pantheon, Bleredd of Greyhawk, Reorx of Krynn, and Onatar of the Sovereign Host of Eberron.
	 
Craft Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared
	 
1st — detect magic, unseen servant
3rd —heat metal, magic weapon
5th — elemental weapon, meld into stone
7th —fabricate, stone shape
9th —creation, legend lore
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Cantrip (Craft Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain the mending cantrip, if you don’t already know it.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Craft Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you become proficient with heavy armor, warhammers, and two tools of your choice.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master Crafter (Craft Domain)</name><text>Also at first level, you gain the ability to weave the divine energies of creation itself into your work. You add your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make to create or repair an item. If you are already proficient in a relevant tool or skill, you add your proficiency from that skill or tool as well, for a total of double your proficiency bonus.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Death Domain</name><text>The Death domain is concerned with the forces that cause death, as well as the negative energy that gives rise to undead creatures. Deities such as Chemosh, Myrkul, and WeeJas are patrons of necromancers, death knights, liches, mummy lords, and vampires. Gods of the Death domain also embody murder (Anubis, Bhaal, and Pyremius), pain (Iuz or Loviatar), disease or poison (Incabulos, Talona, or Morgion), and the underworld (Hades and He!). 
	 
Death Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared
	 
1st — false life, ray of sickness
3rd — blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement
5th — animate dead, vampiric touch
7th — blight, death ward
9th — antilife shell, cloudkill
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 96</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Death Domain)</name><text>When the cleric chooses this domain at 1st level, he or she gains proficiency with martial weapons.
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 96</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Reaper (Death Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, the cleric learns one necromancy cantrip of his or her choice from any spell list. When the cleric casts a necromancy cantrip that normally targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other.
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 96</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Forge Domain</name><text>The gods of the forge are patrons of artisans who work with metal, from a humble blacksmith who keeps a village in horseshoes and plow blades to the mighty elf artisan whose diamond-tipped arrows of mithral have felled demon lords. The gods of the forge teach that, with patience and hard work, even the most intractable metal can transform from a lump of ore to a beautifully wrought object. Clerics of these deities quest to search for objects lost to the forces of darkness, liberate mines overrun by orcs, and uncover rare and wondrous materials necessary to create potent magic items. Followers of these gods take great pride in their work, and they are willing to craft and use heavy armor and powerful weapons to protect them. Deities of this domain include Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.
	  
Forge Domain Spells 
1st — identify, searing smite 
3rd — heat metal, magic weapon 
5th — elemental weapon, protection from energy 
7th — fabricate, wall of fire 
9th — animate objects, creation
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 18</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Forge Domain)</name><text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor and smith’s tools.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Blessing of the Forge (Forge Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to imbue magic into a weapon or armor. At the end of a long rest, you can touch one nonmagical object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest or until you die, the object becomes a magic item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it’s armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it’s a weapon. 
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Grave Domain</name><text>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse’s workings. To desecrate the peace of the dead is an abomination. Deities of the grave include Kelemvor, Wee Jas, the ancestral spirits of the Undying Court, Hades, Anubis, and Osiris. Followers of these deities seek to put wandering spirits to rest, destroy the undead, and ease the suffering of the dying. Their magic also allows them to stave off death for a time, particularly for a person who still has some great work to accomplish in the world. This is a delay of death, not a denial of it, for death will eventually get its due.
	 
Grave Domain Spells
1st — bane, false life
3rd — gentle repose, ray of enfeeblement
5th — revivify, vampiric touch
7th — blight, death ward
9th — antilife shell, raise dead
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Circle of Mortality (Grave Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to manipulate the line between life and death. When you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell to a creature at 0 hit points, you instead use the highest number possible for each die.
	In addition, you learn the spare the dying cantrip, which doesn’t count against the number of cleric cantrips you know. For you, it has a range of 30 feet, and you can cast it as a bonus action.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 20</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Eyes of the Grave (Grave Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to occasionally sense the presence of the undead, whose existence is an insult to the natural cycle of life. As an action, you can open your awareness to magically detect undead. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any undead within 60 feet of you that isn’t behind total cover and that isn’t protected from divination magic. This sense doesn’t tell you anything about a creature’s capabilities or identity.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 20</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Knowledge Domain</name><text>The gods of knowledge — including Oghma, Boccob, Gilean, Aureon, and Thoth — value learning and understanding above all. Some teach that knowledge is to be gathered and shared in libraries and universities, or promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention. Some deities hoard knowledge and keep its secrets to themselves. And some promise their followers that they will gain tremendous power if they unlock the secrets of the multiverse. Followers of these gods study esoteric lore, collect old tomes, delve into the secret places of the earth, and learn all they can. Some gods of knowledge promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention, including smith deities like Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu. 
	 
Knowledge Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — command, identify
3rd — augury, suggestion
5th — nondetection, speak with dead
7th — arcane eye, confusion
9th — legend lore, scrying
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Blessings of Knowledge (Knowledge Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you learn two languages of your choice. You also become proficient in your choice of two of the following skills: Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion.
	Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those skills.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Life Domain</name><text>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy — one of the fundamental forces of the universe — that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei). 
	 
Life Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — bless, cure wounds
3rd — lesser restoration, spiritual weapon
5th — beacon of hope, revivify
7th — death ward, guardian of faith
9th — mass cure wounds, raise dead
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Life Domain)</name><text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Disciple of Life (Life Domain)</name><text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2+the spell’s level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Light Domain</name><text>Gods of light — including Helm, Lathander, Pholtus, Branchala, the Silver Flame, Belenus, Apollo, and Re-Horakhty — promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun. Some of these gods are portrayed as the sun itself or as a charioteer who guides the sun across the sky. Others are tireless sentinels whose eyes pierce every shadow and see through every deception. Some are deities of beauty and artistry, who teach that art is a vehicle for the soul’s improvement. Clerics of a god of light are enlightened souls infused with radiance and the power of their gods’ discerning vision, charged with chasing away lies and burning away darkness.
	 
Light Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — burning hands, faerie fire
3rd — flaming sphere, scorching ray
5th — daylight, fireball
7th — guardian of faith, wall of fire
9th — flame strike, scrying
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Cantrip (Light Domain)</name><text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain the light cantrip if you don’t already know it.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Warding Flare (Light Domain)</name><text>Also at 1st level, you can interpose divine light between yourself and an attacking enemy. When you are attacked by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, causing light to flare before the attacker before it hits or misses. An attacker that can’t be blinded is immune to this feature.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Nature Domain</name><text>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests (such as Silvanus, Obad-Hai, Chislev, Balinor, and Pan) to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves (such as Eldath). Druids revere nature as a whole and might serve one of these deities, practicing mysterious rites and reciting all-but-forgotten prayers in their own secret tongue. But many of these gods have clerics as well, champions who take a more active role in advancing the interests of a particular nature god. These clerics might hunt the evil monstrosities that despoil the woodlands, bless the harvest of the faithful, or wither the crops of those who anger their gods. 
	 
Nature Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — animal friendship, speak with animals
3rd — barkskin, spike growth
5th — plant growth, wind wall
7th — dominate beast, grasping vine
9th — insect plague, tree stride
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Acolyte of Nature (Nature Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you learn one druid cantrip of your choice. You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, or Survival.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Nature Domain)</name><text>Also at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Order Domain</name><text>The Order Domain represents discipline, as well as devotion to the laws that govern a society, an institution, or a philosophy. Clerics of Order meditate on logic and justice as they serve their gods, examples of which appear in the Order Deities table.

Clerics of Order believe that well-crafted laws establish legitimate hierarchies, and those selected by law to lead must be obeyed. Those who obey must do so to the best of their ability, and if those who lead fail to protect the law, they must be replaced. In this manner, law weaves a web of obligations that create order and security in a chaotic multiverse. 

Order Deities
Example Deity	Pantheon
Aureon	Eberron
Bane	Forgotten Realms
Majere	Dragonlance
Pholtus	Greyhawk
Tyr	Forgotten Realms
Wee Jas	Greyhawk 

Domain Spells
1st-level Order Domain feature

You gain domain spells at the cleric levels listed in the Order Domain Spells table. See the Divine Domain class feature in the Player’s Handbook for how domain spells work.

Cleric Level	Spells
1st	command, heroism
3rd	hold person, zone of truth
5th	mass healing word, slow
7th	compulsion, locate creature
9th	commune, dominate person</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Order Domain)</name><text>You gain proficiency with heavy armor. You also gain proficiency in the Intimidation or Persuasion skill (your choice).</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Voice of Authority (Order Domain)</name><text>You can invoke the power of law to embolden an ally to attack. If you cast a spell with a spell slot of 1st level or higher and target an ally with the spell, that ally can use their reaction immediately after the spell to make one weapon attack against a creature of your choice that you can see.

If the spell targets more than one ally, you choose the ally who can make the attack.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Protection Domain</name><text>The protection domain is the purview of deities who charge their followers to shield the weak from the strong. The gods’ faithful dwell in villages and towns on the borderlands, where they help bolster defenses and seek out evils to defeat. These gods believe that a strong shield and a suit of armor is the best defense against evil, second only to a stout mace on hand to respond to any attacks in kind. Deities who grant this domain include Helm, Ilmater, Torm, Tyr, Heironeous, St. Cuthbert, Paladine, Dol Dorn, the Silver Flame, Bahamut, Yondalla, Athena, and Odin. 
Protection Domain Spells 
1st — compelled duel, protection from evil and good 
3rd — aid, protection from poison 
5th — protection from energy, slow 
7th — guardian of faith, Otiluke’s resilient sphere 
9th — antilife shell, wall of force
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency (Protection Domain)</name><text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Shield of the Faithful (Protection Domain)</name><text>Starting at 1st level, you gain the ability to hinder attacks intended for others. When a creature attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. To do so, you must be able to see both the attacker and the target. You interpose an arm, a shield, or some other part of yourself to try to throw the attack off target.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Tempest Domain</name><text>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain — including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor — govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath. 
	 
Tempest Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — fog cloud, thunderwave
3rd — gust of wind, shatter
5th — call lightning, sleet storm
7th — control water, ice storm
9th — destructive wave, insect plague
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Tempest Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Wrath of the Storm (Tempest Domain)</name><text>Also at 1st level, you can thunderously rebuke attackers. When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage (your choice) on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Trickery Domain</name><text>Gods of trickery — such as Tymora, Beshaba, Olidammara, the Traveler, Garl Glittergold, and Loki — are mischief-makers and instigators who stand as a constant challenge to the accepted order among both gods and mortals. They’re patrons of thieves, scoundrels, gamblers, rebels, and liberators. Their clerics are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions. They prefer subterfuge, pranks, deception, and theft rather than direct confrontation.
	 
Trickery Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — charm person, disguise self
3rd — mirror image, pass without trace
5th — blink, dispel magic
7th — dimension door, polymorph
9th — dominate person, modify memory
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Blessing of the Trickster (Trickery Domain)</name><text>Starting when you choose this domain at 1st level, you can use your action to touch a willing creature other than yourself to give it advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: War Domain</name><text>War has many manifestations. It can make heroes of ordinary people. It can be desperate and horrific, with acts of cruelty and cowardice eclipsing instances of excellence and courage. In either case, the gods of war watch over warriors and reward them for their great deeds. The clerics of such gods excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers. Gods of war include champions of honor and chivalry (such as Torm, Heironeous, and Kiri-Jolith) as well as gods of destruction and pillage (such as Erythnul, the Fury, Gruumsh, and Ares) and gods of conquest and domination (such as Bane, Hextor, and Maglubiyet). Other war gods (such as Tempus, Nike, and Nuada) take a more neutral stance, promoting war in all its manifestations and supporting warriors in any circumstance. 
	 
War Domain Spells:
	At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared.
	 
1st — divine favor, shield of faith
3rd — magic weapon, spiritual weapon
5th — crusader’s mantle, spirit guardians
7th — freedom of movement, stoneskin
9th — flame strike, hold monster
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (War Domain)</name><text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>War Priest (War Domain)</name><text>From 1st level, your god delivers bolts of inspiration to you while you are engaged in battle. When you use the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Winter Domain</name><text>Deities of the Winter domain preside over the cold, frigid winds that come with the changing of the season. Some of them represent the chaotic, elemental nature of winter, calling down snowstorms and frigid destruction. Other deities represent the ideals of the changing seasons, with winter bringing the death needed for the rebirth in the spring. Some examples of deities in the Winter domain are the Raven Queen, Auril, and Thrym.

Winter Domain Spells
1st – fog cloud, ice knife (Elemental Evil)
3rd – misty step, snowball swarm 
5th – create food and water, sleet storm
7th – hallucinatory terrain, ice storm
9th – cone of cold, scrying</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Winters Heart: Winter Domain</name><text>Starting at 1st level, you gain the chill touch cantrip. In addition, are considered proficient with Intelligence (Nature) and Wisdom (Survival) checks in snow-covered or ice-covered regions.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiency: Winter Domain</name><text>Also at 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Twilight Domain</name><text>The twilit transition from light into darkness often brings calm and even joy, as the day’s labors end and the hours of rest begin. The darkness can also bring terrors, but the gods of twilight guard against the horrors of the night.


HUMAN CLERIC OF TWILIGHT
Clerics who serve these deities—examples of which appear on the Twilight Deities table—bring comfort to those who seek rest and protect them by venturing into the encroaching darkness to ensure that the dark is a comfort, not a terror.

Twilight Deities
Example Deity	Pantheon
Boldrei	Eberron
Celestian	Greyhawk
Dol Arrah	Eberron
Helm	Forgotten Realms
Ilmater	Forgotten Realms
Mishakal	Dragonlance
Selûne	Forgotten Realms
Yondalla	Halfling

1st-level Twilight Domain feature
You gain domain spells at the cleric levels listed in the Twilight Domain Spells table. See the Divine Domain class feature for how domain spells work.

Twilight Domain Spells
Cleric Level	Spells
1st	faerie fire, sleep
3rd	moonbeam, see invisibility
5th	aura of vitality, Leomund’s tiny hut
7th	aura of life, greater invisibility
9th	circle of power, mislead</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Twilight Domain)</name><text>You gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Eyes Of Night (Twilight Domain)</name><text>You can see through the deepest gloom. You have darkvision out to a range of 300 feet. In that radius, you can see in dim light as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were dim light.

As an action, you can magically share the darkvision of this feature with willing creatures you can see within 10 feet of you, up to a number of creatures equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one creature). The shared darkvision lasts for 1 hour. Once you share it, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest, unless you expend a spell slot of any level to share it again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Vigilant Blessing (Twilight Domain)</name><text>The night has taught you to be vigilant. As an action, you give one creature you touch (including possibly yourself) advantage on the next initiative roll the creature makes. This benefit ends immediately after the roll or if you use this feature again.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Domain: Peace Domain</name><text>The balm of peace thrives at the heart of healthy communities, between friendly nations, and in the souls of the kindhearted. The gods of peace inspire people of all sorts to resolve conflict and to stand up against those forces that try to prevent peace from flourishing. See the Peace Deities table for a list of some of the gods associated with this domain.

Clerics of the Peace Domain preside over the signing of treaties, and they are often asked to arbitrate in disputes. These clerics’ blessings draw people together and help them shoulder one another’s burdens, and the clerics’ magic aids those who are driven to fight for the way of peace.

Peace Deities
Example Deity	Pantheon
Angharradh	Elven
Berronar Truesilver	Dwarven
Boldrei	Eberron
Cyrrollalee	Halfling
Eldath	Forgotten Realms
Gaerdal Ironhand	Gnomish
Paladine	Dragonlance
Rao	 Greyhawk

Domain Spells
1st-level Peace Domain feature
You gain domain spells at the cleric levels listed in the Peace Domain Spells table. See the Divine Domain class feature for how domain spells work.

Peace Domain Spells
Cleric Level	Spells
1st	heroism, sanctuary
3rd	aid, warding bond
5th	beacon of hope, sending
7th	aura of purity, Otiluke’s resilient sphere
9th	greater restoration, Rary’s telepathic bond</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Implement Of Peace (Peace)</name><text>You gain proficiency in the Insight, Performance, or Persuasion skill (your choice).</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Emboldening Bond (Peace)</name><text>You can forge an empowering bond among people who are at peace with one another. As an action, you choose a number of willing creatures within 30 feet of you (this can include yourself) equal to your proficiency bonus. You create a magical bond among them for 10 minutes or until you use this feature again. While any bonded creature is within 30 feet of another, the creature can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw it makes. Each creature can add the d4 no more than once per turn.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>2</level><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Harness Divine Power: Optional Feature</name><text>You can expend a use of your Channel Divinity to fuel your spells. As a bonus action, you touch your holy symbol, utter a prayer, and regain one expended spell slot, the level of which can be no higher than half your proficiency bonus (rounded up). The number of times you can use this feature is based on the level you’ve reached in this class: 2nd level, once; 6th level, twice; and 18th level, thrice. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity</name><text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.
	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.
	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.
	Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses. 
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 58</text></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name><text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Arcane Abjuration (Arcana Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to abjure otherwordly creatures.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol, and one celestial, elemental, fey, or fiend of your choice that is within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw, provided that the creature can see or hear you. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly end its move in a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can only use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.
	After you reach 5th level, when a creature fails its saving throw against your Arcane Abjuration feature, the creature is banished for 1 minute (as in the banishment spell, no concentration required) if it isn’t on its plane of origin and its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold:
	 
Cleric level — Banishes Creature of CR:
5th — 1/2 or lower
8th — 1 or lower
11th — 2 or lower
14th — 3 or lower
17th — 4 or lower
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 125</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Blood Puppet (Blood Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to briefly control a creature’s actions against their will. As an action, you target a Large or smaller creature that has blood within 60 feet of you. That creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or immediately move up to half of their movement in any direction of your choice and make a single weapon attack against a creature of your choice within range. Dead or unconscious creatures automatically fail their saving throw. At 8th level, you can target a Huge or smaller creature.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 101</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Crafter&#39;s Insight (Craft Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into the divine powers of creation.   As an action, you can examine an item and determine if it has any magical properties, as if using detect magic, and what those properties are, as if using identify. 
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Touch of Death (Death Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to destroy another creature’s life force by touch.
	When the cleric hits a creature with a melee attack, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to deal extra necrotic damage to the target. The damage equals 5+twice his or her cleric level.
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinty: Artisan&#39;s Blessing (Forge Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create simple items. 
	You conduct an hour-long ritual that crafts a nonmagical item that must include some metal: a simple or martial weapon, a suit of armor, ten pieces of ammunition, a set of tools. or another metal object (see chapter 5, "Equipment," in the Player’s Handbook for examples of these items). The creation is completed at the end of the hour, coalescing in an unoccupied space of your choice on a surface within 5 feet of you. 
	The thing you create can be something that is worth no more than 100 gp. As part of this ritual, you must lay out metal, which can include coins, with a value equal to the creation. The metal irretrievably coalesces and transforms into the creation at the ritual’s end, magically forming even nonmetal parts of the creation.
	The ritual can create an exact duplicate of a nonmagical item that contains metal, such as a copy of a key, if you possess the original during the ritual.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Path to the Grave (Grave Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to mark another creature’s life force for termination. 
	As an action, you choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you, cursing it until the end of your next turn.. The next timeyou or an ally of yours hits the cursed creature with an attack, the creature has vulnerability to all of the attack’s damage, and then the curse ends.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 20</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Knowledge of the Ages (Knowledge Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into a divine well of knowledge. As an action, you choose one skill or tool. For 10 minutes, you have proficiency with the chosen skill or tool.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Preserve Life (Life Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can’t use this feature on an undead or a construct.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Radiance of the Dawn (Light Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to harness sunlight, banishing darkness and dealing radiant damage to your foes.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol, and any magical darkness within 30 feet of you is dispelled. Additionally, each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Charm Animals and Plants (Nature Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to charm animals and plants.
	As an action, you present your holy symbol and invoke the name of your deity. Each beast or plant creature that can see you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for 1 minute or until it takes damage. While it is charmed by you, it is friendly to you and other creatures you designate.
	 
Charmed:
• A charmed creature can&#39;t attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Order’s Demand (Order Domain)</name><text>You can use your Channel Divinity to exert an intimidating presence over others.

As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each creature of your choice that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn or until the charmed creature takes any damage. You can also cause any of the charmed creatures to drop what they are holding when they fail the saving throw.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Radiant Defense (Protection Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to cloak your allies in radiant armor. 
	As an action, you channel blessed energy into an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you. The first time that ally is hit by an attack within the next minute, the attacker takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Destructive Wrath (Tempest Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to wield the power of the storm with unchecked ferocity.
	When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Invoke Duplicity (Trickery Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create an illusory duplicate of yourself.
	As an action, you create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell). The illusion appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the illusion up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but it must remain within 120 feet of you.
	For the duration, you can cast spells as though you were in the illusion’s space, but you must use your own senses. Additionally, when both you and your illusion are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature, given how distracting the illusion is to the target.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Guided Strike (War Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to strike with supernatural accuracy. When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Winters Kiss (Winter Domain)</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, you can chill your foes to the bone. When you roll cold damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage instead of rolling. Additionally, the creature must make a Constitution saving throw or be slowed until your next turn.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Twilight Sanctuary (Twilight)</name><text>You can use your Channel Divinity to refresh your allies with soothing twilight.

As an action, you present your holy symbol, and a sphere of twilight emanates from you. The sphere is centered on you, has a 30-foot radius, and is filled with dim light. The sphere moves with you, and it lasts for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated or die. Whenever a creature (including you) ends its turn in the sphere, you can grant that creature one of these benefits:

You grant it temporary hit points equal to 1d6 plus your cleric level.
You end one effect on it causing it to be charmed or frightened.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Balm Of Peace (Peace)</name><text>You can use your Channel Divinity to make your very presence a soothing balm. As an action, you can move up to your speed, without provoking opportunity attacks, and when you move within 5 feet of any other creature during this action, you can restore a number of hit points to that creature equal to 2d6 + your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1 hit point). A creature can receive this healing only once whenever you take this action.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><tracker><label>Channel Divinity</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><formula>1</formula></tracker></autolevel><autolevel><level>3</level><slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>4</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat><feat><name>Cantrip Versatility: Optional Feature</name><text>Whenever you reach a level in this class that grants the Ability Score Improvement feature, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this class’s Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>5</level><slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Destroy Undead</name><text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed if its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold
	At 5th level, you destroy undead of CR 1/2 or lower; at 8th level, CR 1 or lower; at 11th level, CR 2 or lower; at 14th level, CR 3 or lower; and at 17th level, CR 4 or lower.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>6</level><slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Spell Breaker (Arcana Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, when you restore hit points to an ally with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can also end one spell of your choice on that creature. The level of the spell you end must be equal to or lower than the level of the spell slot you use to cast the healing spell.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 126</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Crimson Bond (Blood Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to focus on a sample of blood from a creature that is at least 2 ounces, and that has been spilt no longer than a week ago. As an action, you can focus on the blood of the creature to form a bond and gain information about their current circumstances. You know their approximate distance and direction from you, as well as their general state of health, as long as they are within 10 miles of you. You can maintain Concentration on this bond for up to 1 hour.
	During your bond, you can spend an action to attempt to connect with the bonded creature’s senses. The target makes a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. If they succeed, the connection is resisted, ending the bond. You suffer 2d6 necrotic damage. Upon a failed saving throw, you can choose to either see through the eyes of or hear through their ears of the target for a number of rounds equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). During this time, you are blind or deaf (respectively) with regard to your own senses. Once this connection ends, the Crimson Bond is lost.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 101</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Crafter&#39;s Touch (Craft Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your channel divinity to temporarily imbue items with magical powers or to alter the powers of magical items. Until your next short or long rest, a normal item you touch behaves as if it is a common or uncommon magical item of the same type. For example, you could make a normal shield behave as if it were a sentinel shield.
	Alternately, you may make a common, uncommon, or rare magical item behave as if it were a different magical item of the same type and rarity. The item you touch loses its current properties until your next short or long rest, and instead takes on the properties of the item you select. For example, you could make a rod of alertness behave as if it were a rod of absorption.
	If an item’s new properties require attunement, consider that item already attuned if the original item was attuned. 
	You may only have one item under the effects of this feature at a time. Using this feature a second time ends the first effect. 
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Inescapable Destruction (Death Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, the cleric’s ability to channel negative energy becomes more potent. Necrotic damage dealt by the character’s cleric spells and Channel Divinity options ignores resistance to necrotic damage.
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Soul of the Forge (Forge Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, your mastery of the forge grants you special abilities:  
• You gain resistance to fire damage. 
• While wearing heavy armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Sentinel at Death&#39;s Door (Grave Domain)</name><text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to impede death’s progress. As a reaction when you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of you suffers a critical hit, you can turn that hit into a normal hit. Any effects triggered by a critical hit are canceled. 
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 20</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Read Thoughts (Knowledge Domain)</name><text>At 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to read a creature’s thoughts. You can then use your access to the creature’s mind to command it.
	As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can’t use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest.
	If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about) when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute.
	During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and cast the suggestion spell on the creature without expending a spell slot. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the spell.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Blessed Healer (Life Domain)</name><text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2+the spell’s level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Flare (Light Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can also use your Warding Flare feature when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you attacks a creature other than you.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Dampen Elements (Nature Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, when you or a creature within 30 feet of you takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to grant resistance to the creature against that instance of the damage.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Embodiment Of Law (Order Domain)</name><text>You have become remarkably adept at channeling magical energy to compel others.

If you cast a spell of the enchantment school using a spell slot of 1st level or higher, you can change the spell’s casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting, provided the spell’s casting time is normally 1 action.

You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Blessed Healer (Protection Domain)</name><text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others can heal you as well. When you cast a spell with a spell slot and it restores hit points to any creature other than you this turn, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell’s level.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Thunderbolt Strike (Tempest Domain)</name><text>At 6th level, when you deal lightning damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can also push it up to 10 feet away from you.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Cloak of Shadows (Trickery Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to vanish.
	As an action, you become invisible until the end of your next turn. You become visible if you attack or cast a spell.
	 
Invisible:
• An invisible creature is impossible to see without the aid of magic or a special sense. For the purpose of hiding, the creature is heavily obscured. The creature&#39;s location can be detected by any noise it makes or any tracks it leaves.
	
• Attack rolls against the creature have disadvantage, and the creature&#39;s attack rolls have advantage.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: War God&#39;s Blessing (War Domain)</name><text>At 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll, using your Channel Divinity. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Channel Divinity: Winters Aura (Winter Domain)</name><text>Starting at 6th level, you can channel your power to have an area become full of snow and ice. As an action, you can make a 20-foot radius area centered on you become difficult terrain as it becomes covered in ice and snow. You are not affected by this feature, but other creatures must make a Dexterity saving throw whenever they enter or start their turn in the area. On a failed save they fall prone.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Steps Of Night (Twilight)</name><text>You can draw on the mystical power of night to rise into the air. As a bonus action when you are in dim light or darkness, you can magically give yourself a flying speed equal to your walking speed for 1 minute. You can use this bonus action a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Protective Bond (Peace)</name><text>The bond you forge between people helps them protect each other. When a creature affected by your Emboldening Bond feature is about to take damage, a second bonded creature within 30 feet of the first can use its reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the first creature. The second creature then takes all the damage instead.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><tracker><label>Channel Divinity</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><formula>2</formula></tracker></autolevel><autolevel><level>7</level><slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>8</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat><feat><name>Blessed Strikes: Optional Feature</name><text>You are blessed with divine might in battle. When a creature takes damage from one of your cantrips or weapon attacks, you can also deal 1d8 radiant damage to that creature. Once you deal this damage, you can’t use this feature again until the start of your next turn.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Potent Spellcasting (Arcana Domain)</name><text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 126</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Sanguine Recall (Blood Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you can sacrifice a portion of your own vitality to recover expended spell slots. As an action, you recover spell slots that have a combined level equal to or less than half of your cleric level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher. You immediately suffer 1d6 damage per spell slot level recovered. You can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.
	For example, if you’re a 4th-level Cleric, you can recover up to two levels of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots. You then suffer 2d6 damage.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 102</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Craft Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Death Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric’s turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Forge Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with the fiery power of the forge. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 fire damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Potent Spellcasting (Grave Domain)</name><text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 20</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Potent Spellcasting (Knowledge Domain)</name><text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Life Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Potent Spellcasting (Light Domain)</name><text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Nature Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 cold, fire, or lightning damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Order Domain)</name><text>You gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 psychic damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Protection Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Tempest Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 thunder damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Trickery Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 poison damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (War Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric’s turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 damage of the same type dealt by the weapon to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Winter Domain)</name><text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with ice and frost. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 cold damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Divine Strike (Twilight)</name><text>You gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Potent Spellcasting (Peace)</name><text>You add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip. </text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>9</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>10</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Divine Intervention</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.
	Imploring your deity’s aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate.
	If your deity intervenes, you can’t use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.
	At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>11</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>12</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>13</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>14</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>15</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>16</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>17</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Mastery (Arcana Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you choose four spells from the wizard spell list, one from each of the following levels: 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th. You add them to your list of domain spells. Like your other domain spells, they are always prepared and count as cleric spells for you.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 126</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Vascular Corruption Aura (Blood Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you can emit a powerful aura as an action that extends 30 feet out from you that pulses necrotic energy through the veins of nearby foes, causing them to burst and bleed. For 1 minute, any enemy creatures with blood that begin their turn within the aura or enter it for the first time on their turn immediately suffer 2d6 necrotic damage. Any enemy creature with blood that would regain hit points while within the aura only regains half of the intended number of hit points (rounded up).
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Tal&#39;Dorei Campaign Guide p. 102</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Supreme Crafter (Craft Domain)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, when you use your Crafter’s Touch channel divinity feature, you may cause nonmagical items to behave as common, uncommon, rare, or very rare magical items, and you can cause common, uncommon, rare, very rare, or legendary magical items to behave as different magical items of the same type and rarity.  Additionally, you may have up to two items under the effect of Crafter’s Touch at the same time, each requiring a separate usage of your Channel Divinity.
	
Source: DM&#39;s Guild: Craft Domain, p. 2</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Reaper (Death Domain)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, when the cleric casts a Necromancy spell of 1st through 5th level that targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other. If the spell consumes its material components, the cleric must provide them for each target.
	
Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Saint of Forge and Fire (Forge Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, your blessed affinity with fire and metal becomes more powerful: 
• You gain immunity to fire damage.
• While wearing heavy armor, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 19</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Keeper of Souls (Grave Domain)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, you can seize a trace of vitality from a parting soul and use it to heal the living. When an enemy you can see dies within 60 feet of you, you or one creature of your choice that is within 60 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy’s number of Hit Dice. You cn use this feature only if you aren’t incapacitated. Once you use it, you can’t do so again until the start of your next turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 20</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Visions of the Past (Knowledge Domain)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, you can call up visions of the past that relate to an object you hold or your immediate surroundings. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and prayer, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for a number of minutes equal to your Wisdom score and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a spell.
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
	 
Object Reading. Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object’s previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within a number of days equal to your Wisdom score), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.
	 
Area Reading. As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity (a room, street, tunnel, clearing, or the like, up to a 50-foot cube), going back a number of days equal to your Wisdom score. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Supreme Healing (Life Domain)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 60</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Corona of Light (Light Domain)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, you can use your action to activate an aura of sunlight that lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it using another action. You emit bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light 30 feet beyond that. Your enemies in the bright light have disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals fire or radiant damage.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 61</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master of Nature (Nature Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to command animals and plant creatures. While creatures are charmed by your Charm Animals and Plants feature, you can take a bonus action on your turn to verbally command what each of those creatures will do on its next turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Order’s Wrath (Order Domain)</name><text>Enemies you designate for destruction wilt under the combined efforts of you and your allies. If you deal your Divine Strike damage to a creature on your turn, you can curse that creature until the start of your next turn. The next time one of your allies hits the cursed creature with an attack, the target also takes 2d8 psychic damage, and the curse ends. You can curse a creature in this way only once per turn.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Indomitable Defense (Protection Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to two damage types of your choice, choosing from bludgeoning, necrotic, piercing, radiant, and slashing. Whenever you finish a short or long rest, you can change the damage types you chose. 
	As an action, you can temporarily give up this resistance and transfer it to one creature you touch. The creature keeps the resistance until the end of your next short or long rest or until you transfer it back to yourself as a bonus action.
	
Source: Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, p. 3</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Stormborn (Tempest Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed whenever you are not underground or indoors.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 62</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Improved Duplicity (Trickery Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use Invoke Duplicity. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move any number of them up to 30 feet, to a maximum range of 120 feet.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Avatar of Battle (War Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 63</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Champion Of Ice (Winter Domain)</name><text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to Cold damage. You ignore difficult terrain created by ice or snow. You also can tolerate temperatures as low as -50 degrees Fahrenheit without any additional protection. If you wear heavy clothes, you can tolerate temperatures as low as -100 degrees Fahrenheit.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Midnight Shroud (Twilight)</name><text>The twilight that you summon offers a protective embrace: you and your allies have half cover while in the sphere created by your Twilight Sanctuary.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Expansive Bond (Peace)</name><text>The benefits of your Emboldening Bond and Protective Bond features now work when the creatures are within 60 feet of each other. Moreover, when a creature uses Protective Bond to take someone else’s damage, the creature has resistance to that damage.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>18</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots><tracker><label>Channel Divinity</label><type>1</type><resetType>1</resetType><formula>3</formula></tracker></autolevel><autolevel><level>19</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 59</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>20</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots></autolevel><spellAbility>4</spellAbility><spell><name>Bless</name><school>4</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a sprinkling of holy water</materials><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>You bless up to three creatures of your choice within range. Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw. 
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 219</text><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Paladin</sclass><sclass>Soul Binder</sclass></spell><spell><name>Enhance Ability</name><school>8</school><level>2</level><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>fur or a feather from a beast</materials><duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration><text>You touch a creature and bestow upon it a magical enhancement. Choose one of the following effects: the target gains the effect until the spell ends. 
	Bear&#39;s Endurance: The target has advantage on Constitution checks. It also gains 2d6 temporary hit points, which are lost when the spell ends.
	Bull&#39;s Strength: The target has advantage on Strength checks, and his or her carrying capacity doubles.
	Cat&#39;s Grace: The target has advantage on Dexterity checks. It also doesn&#39;t take damage from falling 20 feet or less if it isn&#39;t incapacitated.
	Eagle&#39;s Splendor: The target has advantage on Charisma checks.
	Fox&#39;s Cunning: The target has advantage on Intelligence checks.
	Owl&#39;s Wisdom: The target has advantage on Wisdom checks.
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 237</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Ranger (Primeval Guardian)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Artificer (UA)</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (AE)</sclass><sclass>Ranger</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Fog Cloud*</name><school>2</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration><text>You create a 20-foot-radius sphere of fog centered on a point within range. The sphere spreads around corners, and its area is heavily obscured, It lasts for the duration or until a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses it. 
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the radius of the fog increases by 20 feet for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 243

* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text><sclass>Cleric (Tempest)</sclass><sclass>Cleric (Winter)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Guidance</name><school>3</school><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one ability check of its choice. It can roll the die before or after making the ability check. The spell then ends.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 248</text><roll>1d4</roll><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Healing Word</name><school>5</school><level>1</level><time>1 bonus action</time><range>60 feet</range><v>1</v><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs. 
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 250</text><roll>1d4+%0</roll><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Spellbinder</sclass></spell><spell><name>Prayer of Healing</name><school>5</school><level>2</level><time>10 minutes</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>Up to six creatures of your choice that you can see within range each regain hit points equal to 2d8+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs. 
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 267</text><roll>2d8+%0</roll><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Paladin</sclass></spell><spell><name>Spare the Dying</name><school>7</school><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You touch a living creature that has 0 hit points. The creature becomes stable. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 277</text><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Chronomancer</sclass><sclass>Artificer (E)</sclass></spell><spell><name>Thaumaturgy</name><school>8</school><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><duration>Up to 1 minute</duration><text>You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You create one of the following magical effects within range:
	 • Your voice booms up to three times as loud as normal for 1 minute. 
	• You cause flames to flicker, brighten, dim, or change color for 1 minute. 
	• You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1 minute. 
	• You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous whispers. 
	• You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or window to fly open or slam shut. 
	• You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute. 
	If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1-minute effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 282</text><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer (Witchcraft)</sclass><sclass>Witch</sclass></spell><spell><name>Thunderwave*</name><school>5</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self (15-foot cube)</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn&#39;t pushed. 
	In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell&#39;s effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet. 
	
At Higher Levels: 
	When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 282

* Oath, Domain, or Circle of the Land spell (always prepared)</text><roll>2d8</roll><sclass>Cleric (Tempest)</sclass></spell></class><container><name>Explorer’s Pack</name><text>Includes a backpack, a bedroll, a mess kit, a tinderbox, 10 torches, 10 days of rations, and a waterskin. The pack also has 50 feet of hempen rope strapped to the side of it.</text><value>10.0</value><item><name>Backpack</name><value>2.0</value><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Bedroll</name><value>1.0</value><weight>7.0</weight></item><item><name>Mess kit</name><text>This tin box contains a cup and simple cutlery. The box clamps together, and one side can be used as a cooking pan and the other as a plate or shallow bowl.</text><value>0.2</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Tinderbox</name><text>This small container holds flint, fire steel, and tinder (usually dry cloth soaked in light oil) used to kindle a fire. Using it to light a torch—or anything else with abundant, exposed fuel—takes an action. Lighting any other fire takes 1 minute.</text><value>0.5</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Torch</name><text>A torch burns for 1 hour, providing bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. If you make a melee attack with a burning torch and hit, it deals 1 fire damage.</text><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.01</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Rations (1 day)</name><text>Rations consist of dry foods suitable for extended travel, including jerky, dried fruit, hardtack, and nuts.</text><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.5</value><weight>2.0</weight></item><item><name>Waterskin</name><value>0.2</value><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Hempen rope (50 feet)</name><text>Rope, whether made of hemp or silk, has 2 hit points and can be burst with a DC 17 Strength check.</text><value>1.0</value><weight>10.0</weight></item></container>
<item><name>Chain Mail</name><text>Made of interlocking metal rings, chain mail includes a layer of quilted fabric worn underneath the mail to prevent chafing and to cushion the impact of blows. The suit includes gauntlets.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 145</text><type>3</type><slot>5</slot><value>75.0</value><weight>55.0</weight><ac>16</ac><strength>13</strength><stealth>1</stealth></item><item><name>Warhammer</name><text>Proficiency: martial, warhammer
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>5</type><slot>2</slot><value>15.0</value><weight>2.0</weight><damage1H>1d8</damage1H><damage2H>1d10</damage2H><damageType>1</damageType><weaponProperty>1536</weaponProperty><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><slots>5,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>5,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent></character>
</pc>