<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BwDTTM3IwwwlUHRFN0l4V3pITVE/view -->
<compendium version="5">
<!--Spell Attack rolls assume PROF added to roll, not applicable for Ranged while engaged in Melee range-->
<!--replaced ":" as intro to list with ".", and as in-line text with " - "-->
	<spell>
		<name>AARD</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>15 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Witcher</classes>
		<text>A blast of telekinetic force shoots forth from your hand. All creatures within a 15 foot cone of you must make a Strength saving throw, on a failed save, targets are pushed back 10 feet and knocked prone.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Enhanced - The range of Aard is now a 15 foot sphere with you at the center, and deals 1d4 + your Intelligence modifier force damage. You may cast this sign as a bonus action. If you are under the influence of a Petri's Philter when you cast this, the range increases to 20 feet.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>AXII</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>20 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Witcher</classes>
		<text>Choose a target within 20 feet. That target must make a Wisdom saving throw or glowing white light surrounds their head, and they are stunned until the end of their next turn.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Enhanced - The target becomes an ally of yours, rather than being stunned, until the end of its next turn, moving towards its nearest comrade and attacking it. If there are no comrades available, apply the basic version of the sign instead. OR You cast the spell Command as a first level spell.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>IGNI</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>15 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Witcher</classes>
		<text>A conflagration of flame surges forth from your hand. All creatures within a 15 foot cone of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a fail, they take 1d6 fire damage, on a save, they take half damage (rounded down.)</text>
		<text />
		<text>This damage increases by 1d6 at 6th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Enhanced - A conflagration of flame surges forth from your hand. All creatures within a 15 foot cone of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a fail, they take 1d10 fire damage, on a save, they take half damage (rounded down.) This damage increases by 1d10 at 6th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th level. If a creature fails its saving throw, it catches on fire, and takes 1d4 fire damage at the end of its turn for 1d6 rounds, or until it uses its action to smother the flame.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>QUEN</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>0 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>1 Minute</duration>
		<classes>Witcher</classes>
		<text>Streaks of light orbit your body. You gain temporary hitpoints equal to your level + your Intelligence modifier. You may only have one instance of this sign active at a time.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Enhanced - Add your Intelligence Modifier to AC until the end of your next turn. You may cast this spell as a reaction. You must complete a short or long rest before you can cast the enhanced version of this spell again. IF you are under the influence of a Petri's Philter when you cast this, the bonuses to AC do not stack.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>YRDEN</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>10 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Witcher</classes>
		<text>Glowing runes outline a 10 foot circle around you that lasts for 1d4 + your Intelligence modifier rounds. All creatures within 10 feet of you, or any that move within this radius, must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, they have their speed halved and can’t take bonus actions while within this radius.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Enhanced - All creatures in the radius have disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws, and take 1d4+your Intelligence modifier of psychic damage if they end their turn within the radius. This damage increases by 1d4 at 10th and 15th level.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Moda (Bear School Only)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>10 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Witcher</classes>
		<text>A wall of frozen earth quickly rises straight up out of the ground in front of you. It is 10 feet tall by 15 feet long by 5 feet thick, and has hit points equal to twice your level + Strength modifier, and an AC equal to your Strength modifier. A creature may wear it down to rubble by attacking it. You can break the wall at will, but you must make contact with it. At 5th level, any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the wall must make a Constitution saving throw against your Sign Save DC or take 1d8 cold damage and have its speed halved. This damage increases to 2d8 at level 10, and 3d8 at level 15.</text>
	</spell>
</compendium>